<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[tunaphishy]]></title><description><![CDATA[tunaphishy]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 22:32:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[always eventually right]]></title><description><![CDATA[The most misunderstood Amazon leadership principle is “is usually right.” At first glance this is the surface level meaning. That they are…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/always-eventually-right/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/always-eventually-right/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The most misunderstood Amazon leadership principle is “is usually right.” At first glance this is the surface level meaning. That they are always right. They come into meetings trying to convince everyone of their way of thinking. Always pushing back. Forcing others to submit by sheer will instead of working together to form a shared vision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My interpretation is the saying should be are eventually right. Good leaders arrive at the right answer, maybe not right away but with time. This manifests by meeting everyone’s needs. Making little bets (small iteration cycles). Keeping doors open until they truly need to close them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But maybe that’s not good enough. Maybe you need to be right, and right right now. [[compounding-interest]] dictates that decisions made today are worth more then decisions made later. That means people who get it right the first time are inherently more valuable then the people who eventually make the right decision. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Abundance Mentality and Growth Mentality]]></title><description><![CDATA[before getting this job at Amazon I didn’t believe in myself. I didn’t realize I didn’t believe in myself either. I’m not sure how to…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/abundance-mentality-and-growth-mentality/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/abundance-mentality-and-growth-mentality/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;before getting this job at Amazon I didn’t believe in myself. I didn’t realize I didn’t believe in myself either. I’m not sure how to explain it but I was somewhat resigned to certain tracts in life. I truly thought that some paths in life weren’t available to me. Obviously I’m never going to be an NBA player but that doesn’t mean I can’t achieve what I want to achieve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;difference between abundance and growth&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see them both as opportunities existing but abundance is for external opportunities whereas growth is for internal opportunities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;accepting that you can do anything. but you won’t do everything&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had this conversation with my friend. We truly believe we can do anything now… but we can’t do everything. And that’s okay. There’s something scary but incredibly freeing about that.
There’s so much in this world you’ll never do. You can never do. There’s not enough time. Just thinking about what’s most important to you and then choosing to do those things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me that’s hanging with the people I care about and working on the projects I find interesting. Getting a good night’s sleep, a good workout and a good meal. That’s all you need. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ambiguity Increases with Responsibilities]]></title><description><![CDATA[In software engineering careers, people perceive this to be the ambiguity of the problems you deal with. However, this applies more to your…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/ambiguity-increases-with-responsibilities/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/ambiguity-increases-with-responsibilities/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In software engineering careers, people perceive this to be the ambiguity of the problems you deal with. However, this applies more to your job responsibilities and roles. There’s enough breadth and ambiguity at the higher levels of your career that no two engineer’s day will look exactly alike. Generally, they fall into certain archetypes based on a multitide of factors; interal and external like individual personality types and external reward structures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staff Engineer, Will Larson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Behavior Driven Development]]></title><description><![CDATA[<-INSERT GRAPH-> SPECS -> GENERATOR -> TESTARONIS
normally specifications are created at the beginning of a project and subsequently…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/behavior-driven-development/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/behavior-driven-development/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x3C;-INSERT GRAPH-&gt; SPECS -&gt; GENERATOR -&gt; TESTARONIS
normally specifications are created at the beginning of a project and subsequently forgotten about and become unmaintained.
how many times has a PM or manager come to me about scenarios we’ve changed in the past.
uses technology like Cucumber or Specflow to generate tests from scenarios&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;output&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automated tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigatable websites of specs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;boring paper documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;version control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Be an amateur]]></title><description><![CDATA[TODO: not very thought through
often times when you start something there’s a huge divide between your taste and your ability to create…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/be-an-amateur/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/be-an-amateur/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;TODO: not very thought through
often times when you start something there’s a huge divide between your taste and your ability to create. overcome it and just be an amateur. someone in love with the craft and wear it proudly and [[allow-yourself-to-be-vulnerable]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you spend your life avoiding vulnerability then your work will never truly connect with anyone &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Austin Kleon - Show your Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Baushaus]]></title><description><![CDATA[the principle (at least the only one I learned from this school) that function should inform form. 
I am a relative newcomer to design and…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/baushaus/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/baushaus/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;the principle (at least the only one I learned from this school) that function should inform form.
I am a relative newcomer to design and having a blank page terrifies me. Keeping this principle in mind helps with me with [[dealing-with-analysis-paralysis]].&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[asian masculinity in america]]></title><description><![CDATA[Something I’ve struggled with a lot growing up and to this day.  way of man presents three core traits of traditional masculinity strength…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/asian-masculinity-in-america/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/asian-masculinity-in-america/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve struggled with a lot growing up and to this day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;way of man presents three core traits of traditional masculinity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strength&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;game (determination)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;craftsmanship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paying for your date, getting jacked and fighting dudes, drinking beers. All the other measures of masculinity that are perpetuated by the [[inertia-of-traditions]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Including the ones that pervade American consciousness and prejudice against asian men.
Height, penis size.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;operating despite current day societal views on masculinity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[strive-for-ideals-operate-practically]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;these things are still perpetuated though and just because you are &lt;strong&gt;enlightened TM&lt;/strong&gt; doesn’t mean shit when your [[social-capital]] is still threatened by bullshit ideas of masculinity. Like any other deal with social capital you need to amass some of it yourself before you can influence others. Even just influencing the people around you is enough, because that is what you should be striving for anyways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Way of Man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[California Syndrome]]></title><description><![CDATA[Once I move to California that’s when my real life starts. Once I graduate college… Once I get married… Once I get that promotion … Once I…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/california-syndrome/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/california-syndrome/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Once I move to California that’s when my real life starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I graduate college…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I get married…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I get that promotion …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I retire …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they find that they’ve never really lived at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaiji&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build Tension]]></title><description><![CDATA[Somethings are meant to build anticipation. And then paying off that antcipation. your life can’t be all hits.  Suspense movies are like…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/build-tension/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/build-tension/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Somethings are meant to build anticipation. And then paying off that antcipation. your life can’t be all hits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspense movies are like this. Jump scares are oftentimes derided but if there’s nothing that ever shocks you then the tension building doesn’t ever really amount to anything does it? It’s made scarier because you are anticipating something. Sometimes the scariest scenes don’t come from horror movies. Parasite was so good at this when the poor family was stuck inside the rich family’s house. audiences only remembers peaks and valleys. so while they’ll struggle to remember the scenes leading up to these tense ones, the tense ones are burned forever in their mind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People, balk at having a scheduled love making session. However, because it’s something that is scheduled, you are looking forward to it. Anticipating it. This is antithetical to spontaneous sex that people generally seem to favor and pervades media because media portrays new love and not old love. Considered unromantic and unsexy. Counterpoint is that with spontaneous sex is similar to my jump scare argument. You still anticipate spontaneous sex with the added benefit that you don’t know when it’s coming which increases the tension. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Breaks are Important for Knowledge Work]]></title><description><![CDATA[Diffused vs Focused Learning diffused learning vs focused learning is the concept that you are also learning when you aren’t actively…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/breaks-are-important-for-knowledge-work/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/breaks-are-important-for-knowledge-work/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Diffused vs Focused Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;diffused learning vs focused learning is the concept that you are also learning when you aren’t actively learning and that it is a necessary part of the process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;another reason why butt in seat time is not a good metric for knowledge based work, it just simply isn’t true&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Break Length&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pomodoro breaks utilized during your [[deep-work-habit-chain]]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(10 minutes in between deep work sections and some longer breaks).
Avoid social media during this time. It detracts from what a break is supposed to do. While you are taking a break you are supposed to be recharging and relaxing your mind for the next deep work section. What social media does instead forces a slew of information in your brain that you then need to process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;effective breaks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;figure out what it is that is distracting you from your deep work and dial it down with your break&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoga&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bathroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chat with someone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Workend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bias towards Long Form Media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should bias towards long form media (you trend towards short form like TikTok which KILLS your attention span)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long form media should driving strategic thinking and mental models. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short form media should be driving tactical decisions and techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Weekend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human made construct. Yet there’s some elegance to it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Career Cold Start Algorithm]]></title><description><![CDATA[joining a new job is difficult. you have a massive knowledge defecit and no preexisting relationships. you want to want maximize your…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/career-cold-start-algorithm/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/career-cold-start-algorithm/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;joining a new job is difficult. you have a massive knowledge defecit and no preexisting relationships. you want to want maximize your initial impact while minimizing collateral damage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;process&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first step is to find someone on the team and ask for 30 minutes with them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the first 25 minutes: ask them to tell you everything they think you should know. Take copious notes. Only stop them to ask about things you don’t understand. Always stop them to ask about things you don’t understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the next 3 minutes: ask about the biggest challenges the team has right now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the final 2 minutes: ask who else you should talk to. Write down every name they give you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeat the above process for every name you’re given. Don’t stop until there are no new names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Everything they think you should know&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sum of the answers from the first 25 mins will not give you a complete picture of the team’s work. That will take months to develop. But they will give you a framework for integrating new information more quickly, which will speed up how fast you ramp. It will also heavily over index on the areas of work under active discussion, which will help you dive in productively to the most critical discussions immediately. The nature of what people choose to discuss is a very valuable signal about the problems the team face, as it may be about the work, the organization, or process. Finally, it will give you a sense of the language and terminology that can very often be a barrier to working smoothly with teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What are the biggest challanges the team has right now&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answers from the second question give you a cheat sheet on how to impress the team with early positive impact. Some of the things you’ll hear will take time to fix, such as “we need a bigger team” or “our infrastructure isn’t scaling.” Those are important and it will be good for the team to hear you internalize those challenges. But a surprising number of the issues you’ll hear repeatedly will be things you can easily help with, like “we waste a bunch of time in meetings every week” or “we need a dedicated conference room.” I start with the latter as quickly as I can because those are the types of things teams often neglect to prioritize, in spite of a compounding negative impact on progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What should I talk to?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third question will give you a valuable map of influence in the organization. The more often names show up and the context in which they show up tends to provide a very different map of the organization than the one in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://boz.com/articles/damn-the-org-chart.html&quot;&gt;org chart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the value I just described, the greatest value in this process isn’t in the answers — it is in the asking. Taking these meetings and listening shows proper respect for the team that’s in place. It can be hard to remember, but while you may be insecure about taking a new role because you feel like you’re at a disadvantage, the people you’re speaking with may also be unsure about you taking that role and what it means for them. Demonstrating mutual respect builds the trust required to make progress.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Code Reviews]]></title><description><![CDATA[reviews protect against the natural state of entropy that code tends to fall into. 
use this guide to refactor and to review other’s code…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/code-reviews/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/code-reviews/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;reviews protect against the natural state of entropy that code tends to fall into.
use this guide to refactor and to review other’s code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Gather Context&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the SIM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Draw code diagram | envision the grand scheme of code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;conventions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prefer readability over everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid comments
comments shouldn’t explain what something does. the source code does this and commenting is a crutch for poor readability. if you have to have comments it should be to explain why something is the way it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prefer excessive logging and metrics
logging business logic is a good idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Package&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Multiple responsibilities (will this package change for multiple reasons)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Dispersed responsibilities (will a change effect multiple packages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid YAGNI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inheritence → Favor Composition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Large classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid coupling classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember Injection, Non null&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid Object Instantiation and Favor Factories or Builders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation need not exist at compile time (???)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vary return type based on inputs Compact API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return type can be subtyped eg Return a different type of Enum based on size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is named eg getInstance()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control instance creation eg object pools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimize Accessibility of Classes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design a minimal public API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce accessibility of internals as much as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change structure however you like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize APIs you have to maintain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decoupling = develop|test|modify in parallel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decrease risk of building large systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Function&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Pointless Indirection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prefer defensive programming, validate inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;prefer smaller parameter sizes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try more methods that use different parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try helper methods that encompass the parameter list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try parameter objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prefer interfaces in params over classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;avoid side effects and mutations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything that returns a value should have no observable side effects!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;return defensive copies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Flag Parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Optionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prefer Method References &gt; Lambdas &gt; Anonymous Classes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lambdas essentially do the job of anonymous classes but with a lot less boilerplate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Method references should be used over lambdas. They provide a bit more documentation and are generally less verbose. This isn’t always the case however.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid varargs for performance issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use optionals to force clients to deal with missing data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid global data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid strings over more precise datatypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prefer immutability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid primitive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid clumps (data that tends to appear together but not grouped)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid ethereal (temporary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid chaining (person.name.last)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Exception Handling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favor Try with Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid exceptions over conditions (performance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Checked Exceptions for Recoverable States and Unchecked for Programming Errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Switches or Loops and prefer functional programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;avoid (complex) conditionals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try early exits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try strategy pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try special case object pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean Code - Robert Martin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Java - Joshua Bloch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactoring - Martin Fowler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Code Documentation]]></title><description><![CDATA[documentation is the act of sharing knowledge tenets one diagram = one story
documentation should  exploit authoritative sources (code base…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/code-documentation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/code-documentation/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;documentation is the act of sharing knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;tenets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one diagram = one story
documentation should &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exploit authoritative sources (code base)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enrich authoritative sources (annotations as tags, standardized git commits)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;why is is documentation important?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;code tenure vs developer tenure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;average developer tenure is 3 years
average code tenure is 13 years.
documentation is meant to bridge this gap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;play the role of a curator. you are taking the infinite knowledge of development and your project and crafting a useful narrative for your team and stakeholders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;software architect’s goal is to minimize the human effort required to build and maintain software. thus you should foucs on the speed of delivery.
but not just for you and not just for right now.
but for your coworkers and for the future&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the actual act of writing code is easy. the difficulty of coding comes from continuous [[decision-making]]. backing those decisions is knowledge which is required to make informed decisions. thus the efficient storage and retrieval of knowledge is important. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;documents in every code project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;readme &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;installation instructions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getting started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to contribute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;glossary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;ideas&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[behavior-driven-development]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;annotations as generic documentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design patterns (@adapter that links to GoF pattern)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;callouts (@hack, @provider)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tags (@provider find all dependencies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;decision log&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explains rationales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;formalized git (semi formal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate change log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explains rationales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allows command line tools exploitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Compounding Interest]]></title><description><![CDATA[The ability for small investments made everyday to build overtime to something significant overtime.  Predicated by two ideas: a dollar…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/compounding-interest/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/compounding-interest/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The ability for small investments made everyday to build overtime to something significant overtime. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predicated by two ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a dollar today is worth more then tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your investments building on themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this applies to everything in life. skills you want to develop. relationships you want to nurture. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Content Creation]]></title><description><![CDATA[goals  you are filming and documenting your interesting life and then crafting a narrative around it.  look back on my life try new things…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/content-creation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/content-creation/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;goals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; you are filming and documenting your interesting life and then crafting a narrative around it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look back on my life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try new things, experiment, projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just film my life casually and craft a story in the cutting room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;film [[habit-chain]]&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify purpose (I’m eating good ass food, having good time with rena)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify style based on purpose (tiktok trends, haegreendal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gather shots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;establishing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;favor motivated camera movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;edit process&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;day to day [[habit-chain]]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;export footage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cut favorites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cut on action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stabilize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;edit day [[habit-chain]]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;identify story&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;select music: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hellothematic.com/&quot;&gt;thematic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;group scenes &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start audio 2-3 frames before next clip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain eyeline between zoom-ins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;color grade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;youtube strategy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;purpose → create online prescence that requires effort, document mines and rena’s life
content → time periods of life, project
style → deemphasize face and voice, korean style vlogs… except faster cadence. more jokes. more camera play. emphasize audio
wide to detail cadence
timelines → videos should take a week to a month
narrative → life, inner issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;editing things I want to learn&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creating a narrative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;color grading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voice overs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;draw effects on my videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proper settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better audio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gimbal shots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screen shot film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone chest mount with backpack?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using better equipment again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;inspos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/watch?v=VRBmm6RKtVM&amp;#x26;feature=share&quot;&gt;https://youtube.com/watch?v=VRBmm6RKtVM&amp;#x26;feature=share&lt;/a&gt; - youtube cinematography
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMe43g33y/&quot;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMe43g33y/&lt;/a&gt; - what my camera sees
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reel/CN7YrJro-_B/?igshid=uvphu1v4v8f6&quot;&gt;https://www.instagram.com/reel/CN7YrJro-_B/?igshid=uvphu1v4v8f6&lt;/a&gt; - shadow’s showing
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeVSRSrN/&quot;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeVSRSrN/&lt;/a&gt; - camera angle with mirror
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMegcwhxb/&quot;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMegcwhxb/&lt;/a&gt; - couples photos while traveling!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeG6Ejtd/&quot;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeG6Ejtd/&lt;/a&gt; - korean mood edit
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMenPXVft/&quot;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMenPXVft/&lt;/a&gt; - 3D zoom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Consumption Strategy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passive streams that feed me inspiration and updates. I should be conscious in my consumption to see how it can fuel my life. Don’t mindlessly scroll. Identify why you like something, and categorize accordingly so it can be back referenced when a project down the line requires it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Youtube - Cooking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram - Art, Design, Home Decor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tiktok - Trends, Youth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;consumption types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;targeted (how does this help my project overall, on my tasks for the next few days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curated passive consumption (thoughtful.. what do I like. what don’t I, what project can this contribute to)
the science of software engineering often involves the efficient storage and retrieval of data. it makes sense to apply similar principals to personal knowledge management. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cultures as a form a natural evolution]]></title><description><![CDATA[the example I’m reading about right now is japanese bath culture. They have a very rich communal bath culture. They’ve taken baths for…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/cultures-as-a-form-of-natural-evolution/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/cultures-as-a-form-of-natural-evolution/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;the example I’m reading about right now is japanese bath culture. They have a very rich communal bath culture. They’ve taken baths for millenia, adding things to this culture that enhance this experience and discarding things that don’t. They bathe in natural hot springs rich in minerals. To reuse bath water they shower beforehand. Their onsen clothing is light and airy. Bath accesories are made out of hinoki wood which is naturally rot and water resistant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is oftentimes why food developed over the years in a culture oftentimes taste so much better then fusion food. It’s because it’s had the opportunity to go through the cycles of iteration to perfect the style of food. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the inertia of traditions will cause inoptimal things. And things are made for Arbitrary decisions. The guy who made doctor 24 hour oncalls regularly did cocaine. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Continuously Iterate on Technical Quality]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rather then a failure, closing the gap between your target and technical quality is a routine, essential part of effective engineering…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/continously-iterate-on-technical-quality/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/continously-iterate-on-technical-quality/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather then a failure, closing the gap between your target and technical quality is a routine, essential part of effective engineering leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is similar to the ideals espoused in Refactoring by Martin Fowler. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;litany of strategies for this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hotspots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;best practices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;he talks about letting these fail because they often don’t work out and starting small. I feel like my attempts at these were failures. I oftentimes see process changes fail for project management because they depend on developers changing their working processes and there’s inertia to this. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leverage points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;align technical vectors (strategy and vision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;measuring quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quality teams &amp;#x26; programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Decision Making]]></title><description><![CDATA[frameworks for guiding decision making [minimize-regret]  tenets [decision-making-length-should-be-proportional-to-importance]]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/decision-making/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/decision-making/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;frameworks for guiding decision making&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[minimize-regret]] &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tenets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[decision-making-length-should-be-proportional-to-importance]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept Artist Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[design guide from designs, identify areas of things you don’t know how to draw! project artstyle style lines palette rendering processing…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/concept-artist-habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/concept-artist-habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;design guide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from designs, identify areas of things you don’t know how to draw!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;artstyle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;palette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rendering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;character&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create bio: 1 liner?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;create style guide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;clothing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;what am I trying to convey?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;character traits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aspects of character design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alternative character outfits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;game moments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what technique can I use to influence above that I’ve never done before?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;painting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thumbnails
pallete
composition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;workflow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Texture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sketch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proportion and composition (Pencil R6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;details (HB)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporate Visual Language
Direction, Focial Point, Contrast, Message (Don’t fucking cheat me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ink&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ink Details
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZzgrOMCd380&quot;&gt;Confidence. Thiccness. Color. Suggestions.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeGhD1wp/&quot;&gt;https://vm.tiktok.com/ZMeGhD1wp/&lt;/a&gt; - suggestion (avoid lines where they aren’t needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duplicated Layer (Color Change, Gaussian blur)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Base Colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Render
build up shapes instead of lines. distill into as simple of shapes as you can that still allow the image to read &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shadow (Multiply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transition Shadow (Soft Brush)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard Shadows (Pen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlight (Overlay, Screen)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light Purple for Skin, Brownish Red for Hair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transition Shadow (Soft Brush)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard Highlights (Pen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-Processing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve|Color Correction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light Smearing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chromatic Aberration|Lens Blur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Curate your Input Streams Carefully]]></title><description><![CDATA[Because [there-is-an-overwhelming-amount-of-information-in-the-world] this practice is very important.
cal newport talked about this a lot…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/curate-your-input-streams-carefully/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/curate-your-input-streams-carefully/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Because [[there-is-an-overwhelming-amount-of-information-in-the-world]] this practice is very important.
cal newport talked about this a lot in digital minimalism. his take is oftentimes to delete these things entirely. you don’t need them. although his ultimate position was just above (to curate carefully). throwing the baby out with the bathwater imo. stands in juxtaposition with austin’s show your work where you [[participate-in-communities]] so you can take advantage of social media! the ability to connect with anyone in the world and share your work. so find a balance. curate your input streams carefully. give more then you get. talk with people. show up everyday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Social Media as Mediums for Gathering Information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tiktok&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really really like tiktok as a medium for some reason. it has huge massive flaws that I think about a lot. right now it seems like the ultimate manifestation of all the worst parts of an [[attention-economy]]. extreme ease of use. bite size information blips. the way people speak on it is oftentimes insufferable. lots of superiority on this medium as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yet I find myself continously getting inspired by it
sense of communities due to the way the algorithm tends to group like minded people together
“organic” exposure to other subjects I am unfamilliar with
constant appeals to pathos over logos. contrast with communities that I generally interact or used to interact with. like reddit, blind or other dev communities.
creative barrier to entry that is high enough that it filters out a lot of low effort content yet is low enough that people that generally wouldn’t generate content for a community like youtube still participate. would say it exists in a space between youtube and instagram.  not a huge fan of instagram stories in general. because of how low low low effort they are and the vapidness of what they communicate. but I think they’re good for conversation hooks. letting people ask me about my cute doggo and such.
Tiktok is king of using filmmaking and aesthetics to convey tone and atmosphere. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reddit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;why reddit is oftentimes pretty shitty and I’ve blocked it on every single &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another predator in the [[attention-economy]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pseudo intellectualism and a sense of superiority because of it. FACTS NOT FEELINGS. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;truth by consensus, a byproduct of the upvote|downvote system.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bias towards low effort, low substance material (man I’m talking about this a lot)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a huge bias against self promotion which stands in contrast with tiktok where it’s celebrated. I can see both sides of this argument because it’s fairly annoying to wade through a bunch of people trying to sell you something but I like the way that tiktok celebrates putting yourself out there and to [[allow-yourself-to-be-vulnerable]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second hand opinions. try to focus on primary sources. not secondary sources. aka take the facts and come to your own observations. stop basing your opinions on other people’s opinions. don’t let other people tell you how to feel. (for research… not when chatting or things of that nature)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;rss feeds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are some misc articles I get sent, blogs I want to keep track of that exist in different spheres and just newsletters I want to keep up with like the latest Gatsby news.
for this I’ll use a simple RSS feed. it’s the ultimate in curation since you have to actively add things to your feed instead of an algorithm feeding it to you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one big issue is dealing with major news sites where the rate of articles they send out make it fairly difficult to filter the ones you actually care about. sadly, just get rid of them. the noise to signal ratio isn’t there. a big loss for things like japanese media (siliconera comes to mind) that you don’t have other organic sources of information for (actually tiktok is filling this void quite nicely) but that’s okay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cal Newport - Digital Minimalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Austin Kleon - Show your Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dealing with Analysis Paralysis]]></title><description><![CDATA[Something I struggle with a lot. I constantly find new ways to do this. From infinite research to my latest way of creating ‘mood boards…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/dealing-with-analysis-paralysis/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/dealing-with-analysis-paralysis/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Something I struggle with a lot. I constantly find new ways to do this. From infinite research to my latest way of creating ‘mood boards’. Just put something out there. You will know if it doesn’t fit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;remember, it is an arbitrary world&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I get older the more I realize things aren’t the result of thoughtful designs but arbitrary decisions. This and the fact that there’s an inertia with tradition that means decisions made arbitrarily will continue to perpetuate by virtue of having existing and persisted up until that time.
Have the audacity to say the world isn’t representing me and I will make it happen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;remember, your personal value system is valid&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically people often experience social anxiety because they take rejection
personally IE it’s a measure of your social value or rank.
This is rooted in a belief that other people can measure your value and that measure is more important than yours. If you are living by your own value system than other people’s opinions don’t become nearly as important so their rejection doesn’t lower your self esteem. If you truly believe in your own values than you can approach people, measure their value, invite them into your world and not take it too personally if they say no.
don’t forget to [[allow-yourself-to-be-vulnerable]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;avoid self help books → waste of time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An issue I have with a lot of self help books, productivity managers comes down to the same thing; would this time be better spent actually doing the activity itself? This stems from a disdain that I have for a lot of the self help community. People who’s job is it to tell people how to be more productive instead of being productive. Why read a book on how to read a book, when I can just read a book. Especially since I have spent so so much time reading these self help books to stuffing my face with chips and playing Apex Legends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;bias for action&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITERATION, ITERATION, ITERATION.
Be more confident in yourself. Put something down. It’s easier to enunciate what’s wrong with what’s in front of you then what’s wrong with what’s in your head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;time box yourself&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emotions are affect heuristics, they help you make decisions more quickly
the amount of time you spend researching a decision is a decision within itself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;divorce your ego from your work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seperate yourself from your ideas, your work, your legacy. They are not you.
Does that mean you can’t be proud of these things. Feel shame for them?
Yes and no. They are one part of you. One part of this world. [[your-work-does-not-speak-for-itself]] but that is in the context of presenting ideas to other in an attempt at persuasian.
When it comes to putting your work out there in the first place. Always remember. You are not your work. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Decision Making Length Should be Proportional to Importance]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s easy to spend too much time thinking about the things that don’t matter. 
Remember the pareto principle or the 80/20 rule.
Aim for good…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/decision-making-length-should-be-proportional-to-importance/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/decision-making-length-should-be-proportional-to-importance/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to spend too much time thinking about the things that don’t matter.
Remember the pareto principle or the 80/20 rule.
Aim for good, not perfect. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deep Work Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[habit chain play music work pomodoro for 50:10 [breaks-are-important-for-knowledge-work] remove all distractions focus on one task at a time]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/deep-work-habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/deep-work-habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;habit chain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;play music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pomodoro for 50:10 [[breaks-are-important-for-knowledge-work]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove all distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus on one task at a time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Design Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[[habit-chain]s for a variety of open ended tasks Research Habit Chain define problem and time to research gather artifacts summarize…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/design-habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/design-habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;[[habit-chain]]s for a variety of open ended tasks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Research Habit Chain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define problem and time to research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gather artifacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;summarize artifacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify additional questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pull similarities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;summarize artifacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;answer next question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Product Design Habit Chain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MVP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;UX Design Habit Chain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User Flows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wire Frames&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hick’s law:&lt;/strong&gt; the more choices you gie to a user, the more time will be consumed in making the decisions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Visual Design Habit Chain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;general&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language (moods, themes, emotions) remember [[baushaus]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;palette&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;base colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://maketintsandshades.com&quot;&gt;tints and shades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gradients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;typography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two fonts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elevation and shading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;flair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;animations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;transitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3d effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;specific&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lofi page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hifi components&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hifi page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;developer [[habit-chain]]&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;web tenet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;favor HTML|CSS over Javascript solutions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;design flow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;define the problem. keep crafting the problem statement until the solution becomes clear &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define Options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick a solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify remaining ambiguity problems with answers, repeat step 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify volatility &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify generality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;front end flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;atoms -&gt; pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define volatility -&gt; interactivity, things likely to change during development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define generality -&gt; shared components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;back end flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[test-driven-development]]&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Effective altruism]]></title><description><![CDATA[A philsophy for philantropists to attempt to do as much good for the world as effectively as possible. This stands in contrast with how…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/effective-altruism/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/effective-altruism/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A philsophy for philantropists to attempt to do as much good for the world as effectively as possible. This stands in contrast with how people generally pick charities which is to pick something that they are personally close with. The issue with that in somewhere like the United States is that if you usually in a fairly privileged position so the issues you are close trend towards other demographics of similar privilege. Boba asians was something that struck particularly close to me given I was a pretty big advocate for the cultural masculinity issues in the United States that asian men in deal with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is that really a good use of my time? That asian dudes are struggling to get laid? Crass and a reduction of the actual issues and arguments but the point is there are other things that asians deal with that have higher priority like Stop Asian hate where I can still tackle things that are close to me while dealing with high impact issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a common argument for BLM to rally other races around them and spotlight their issue. Black people are effectively being executed by the police legally. Nothing else matters until this is dealt with. However, take that argument worldwide though and it again forces one to shift priorities, for example Uighar Concentration Camps or the famous Bill Gates example of dealing with Malaria in Africa. Some examples of the biggest strife in the world in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Will it Actually Payoff?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think one issue with applying a “Mr. Worldwide” argument to this is that what am I really going to do to help Uighar Concentration Camps or Malaria in Africa?  I can rally support to force the government to act on worldwide issues but other then that… not much. BLM is an American issue and I’m an American. I can march on the streets, donate to local BLM chapters, convince neighbhors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;you cannot save everyone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had a conversation with my mentor where he told me that you have to bet on the right horses. That their team was fairly good at sniffing out people who aren’t going to make it and thus won’t invest too much effort getting too too close with them The reason is it creates a conflict of interests if this person comes to you for feedback or as an advocate for getting to the next level. What do you do when you you personally like someone but they just aren’t very good at their job and they want you to pitch for them? Do you tell them directly? Abstain? It’s kind of like not feeding the trolls.  it’s all about priorities and where to put your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is it right to help the people who are already doing well? Shouldn’t you invest time into trying to get people to succeed? When my team’s big project at Amazon went through a crisis and our junior developers went through hell it was because [[during-crisis-the-vulnerable-are-hit-harder]]. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fear is that it won’t payoff. In this specific example the company has an up and out mental model. Meaning that you have a limited amount of time to actually help this person before they get the axe anyways. Meanwhile this is taking away time from developing yourself or others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also just sucks… It’s so hard teaching people who aren’t apt for it. If I am trying to [[seek-work-that-energizes-you]], then it definitely points me towards helping the capable if for the only reason that it feels good to see other people succeed because of you and it sucks to see people you try to help fail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;reconciling effective altruism and fire&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/EffectiveAltruism/comments/jt86sp/effective_altruism_and_retiring_early_reconciling/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/EffectiveAltruism/comments/jt86sp/effective&lt;em&gt;altruism&lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt;retiring&lt;/em&gt;early_reconciling/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[effective-altruism]] and FIRE both acknowledge that the mindless accumulation of wealth and material possessions is pointless. Then what do you do with all your extra money. Do I try to help the world… or help myself.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Eji]]></title><description><![CDATA[appearance gold chains name doesn’t have a whole lot of thought put into it. It’s vaguely asian (japanese) sounding and sounds like edgy…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/eji/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/eji/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;appearance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gold chains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;name doesn’t have a whole lot of thought put into it. It’s vaguely asian (japanese) sounding and sounds like edgy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eji was a politician? too young for that… an aspiring one? someone who can influence at the very least. popular? wanted to change the world.
eji’s got an ottermode build. fairly lanky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eji struggles to control how he feels. this reflects in his mental battles. they don’t build up and unleash like it does for sei. he attempts to inhibit them. bottle them up. breathing exercises. but it doesn’t work. it leaks out. his interpretation of control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sei informs him that he needs to let emotions out. let them flow and feel them fully. only then can he control them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;eji and sei&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eji and [[sei]]‘s story is a personal one. a story about regret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sei likes traditional first wave diner bitter coffee. eji has him try new third wave coffee. visibly makes a face “it’s sour”. it’s not bad. it’s just not coffee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eji and sei are both hardworkers. eji is more callous though. youthful. brash. headstrong. he’s like the sun. a big theme is their bond together. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[deliberate practice for knowledge work]]></title><description><![CDATA[to mindfully practice an art. forces you to become aware of your flaws insteadly of mindlessly repeating them. useful for training…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/deliberate-practice-for-knowledge-work/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/deliberate-practice-for-knowledge-work/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;to mindfully practice an art. forces you to become aware of your flaws insteadly of mindlessly repeating them. useful for training fundamentals.
a flaw of [[habit-chain]]s is that they innately ask you to perform a task mindlessly. that’s what gives them value. however, for work that you are actively trying to improve you need to deliberately practice.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/beginners-guide-deliberate-practice&quot;&gt;https://jamesclear.com/beginners-guide-deliberate-practice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;things to help deliberate practice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;short iteration cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instant feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;fundamentals for knowlegdge work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recall (meant to overcome active inhibition properly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problem decomposition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enhancing text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;types of deliberate practice for knowledge workers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spaced repetition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leetcode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constellations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;task estimation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Digital Constellation]]></title><description><![CDATA[why write notes in this style tailored: to your learning style, interests, thought processes curated: how many times did you look up a…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/digital-constellation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/digital-constellation/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;why write notes in this style&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tailored: to your learning style, interests, thought processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curated: how many times did you look up a recipe… only to have to filter through all the shit recipes people post online. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distilled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[writing-is-the-only-thing-that-matters]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is beautiful… I love just looking at these graphs &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;interconnected information &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unique ideas and insights. ideas in isolation aren’t that interesting. in fact they are more then likely derivative and already thought of. the way ideas link, contrast and intertwine is what makes them interesting. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organic spaced repetition. you naturally stumble back onto ideas you’ve had before via this style of notetaking thus keeping those mental models fresh in your mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;difference with traditional note taking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional notetaking has two general disadvantages. It starts with hypothesis first. You research to support this hypothesis instead of letting inspiration, insights guide your theories backed by your already existing body of information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the second disadvantage is that having notes be easily accessible necessitates an organization system which is generally a hierarchy system with a taxonomy of folders and classifications. this isolates ideas from each other and prevents one from being able to create unique or novel connections instead forced into already existing classifications of knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;tenets for tending to your digital constellation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes should be fairly conceptual and general in nature. this helps relate ideas together irrespective of context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes should be declarative. they should assert an opinion. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes should be atomic. use a wet and dry method. if you find yourself writing about a concept twice then extract into a common note. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes should be accompanied with a visual. aids in synthesis of ideas and leverages other cognitive models for learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes should be associated with tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes should attempt to connect ideas together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;these notes rarely reflect my final or even my actual thoughts. some may be contradictory to what I think. however, to fully empower this method of notetaking I need to be able to link ideas, reconcile conflicting ideas or even discredit some of them. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;[[baushaus]] for my digital constellation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the graphs and interconnected ideas are what draw me to this style of notetaking moreso then learning in public and tending to ideas over time
the graph looks like stars in the sky and the way the interconnect look like constellations.
this informed the design process to give things a sort of space theme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;integrating (private) work topics into&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constellation exists to link together conceptual ideas to birth unique ideas and insights. the nature of the input and output means that I am only putting in general, conceptual notes in here. Nothing inherent to a project itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;natural clusters in constellations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because your mind tends to always come back to the same subject by following your interest it’s a lot easier to keep up with motivation(something I struggle with). Notes naturally tend to cluster around those interests and because your zettlekesten is permanent you are always contributing and furthering something. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By forming these clusters you organically [[seek-work-that-energizes-you]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;art in the constellations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gather ideas in one place. Connecting them in novel ways. Let them produce ideas for you. Gather the best ideas from games you played. Stories you read visuals from movies. The coolest scene from moody was stabbing in the background. but it also allows you to develop ideas in parallel. This means you have multiple projects cooking. But like academic work there’s mechanical steps that need to be done. Instead of rearranging ideas and deleting redundant sentences. You are filming shots. Or you are drawing some lines.  Remember the Pareto principal for short films is the strength of the script. It can apply again to mechanical work but it’s like 80 percent of the 20 percent. Numbers may be off but the point is some things are higher Impact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Gardens, Maggie Appleton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zettlekestan, Luhhman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Write Smart Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Favor Depth of Experience over Breadth]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s a different kind of a joy, and an experience onto itself by focusing on depth over breadth. Like your monogamous relationship and…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/favor-depth-of-experience-over-breadth/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/favor-depth-of-experience-over-breadth/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s a different kind of a joy, and an experience onto itself by focusing on depth over breadth. Like your monogamous relationship and savoring the growth of one individual overtime instead transient superficial idiosyncrasies of a group of people. Deeply exploring an individual dishs and discovering its depth and appreciating the nuance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;appreciating a material life&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a common line of thought that you should favor experiences over material possessions. This comes from a rejection of consumerism and the belief that a life rich in experiences is one way to [[minimize-regret]]. However, there are several flaws with this line of thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can acquire a deep appreciation for material possessions. This is a philosophy touted by Marie Kondo often. Mindlessly consuming material posessions is bad. People focus on the consuming material posessions part. The true evil is the mindlessly part. Acquiring material posessions with intent, appreciating them, taking proper care of them all lead to a healthier relationship with material goods. Minimalism often flies too far in the opposite direction where you pare down as many items as you possibly can. However this oftentimes lead to outsourcing different parts of your life. For example if you pared down your toolkit and now you needed to borrow a hammer from a neighbhor. Although the idea of community items to reduce overall in the consumption in the world is admirable t at oftentimes isn’t really the goal or intent of reducing how much stuff you have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;collector’s fallacy but make it for experiences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes there’s a collector’s fallacy with experiences as well. Acquiring a list of experiences, things you’ve done just to say you’ve done them. Showing off pictures on social media. &lt;em&gt;expound on this more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;random bullshit that most people fill their lives with&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought a lot about whether or not I’d invest time into learning how to rock climb. today we’re supposed to ride go karts. That lead me to think about how we’ve been doing a lot of fun but random activities. I wonder if this is how people generally live their lives. Going from one fun activitiy to the next. Random things that hold your interest until you die. It’s fine. This passage reads like it’s mocking that line of thought but it’s not. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I can’t help but think that people would be happier if they found more depth in their lives. This is antithetical to finding your passion being a poor way to live though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;deep work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;everyday I do the same thing over and over. repetition is to be celebrated. it’s the only way to achieve depth or anything meaningful in society. Usually, this is performed naturally &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;as it relates to my career as a software engineer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the common advice for software engineers online is after around a few years, start looking for a new job. that is because it’s the fastest way for you to accelerate your paycheck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;however, you always have the opportunity to gather more exposure. but once you sacrifice your chance at depth (for certain things) it’s gone. leave a team and your job’s on the market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;my mentor suggested I work really hard for a few years to get to a career level and just chill out for a bit. I wonder if that is what I should be doing. Feels like [[california-syndrome]] Syndrome where I’m putting off my real life until I can achieve this goal. There’s a defined end date but for most people it’s a few years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Subtle Art of How Not to Give a Fuck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Five Love Languages]]></title><description><![CDATA[people express and receive love differently. identify how your loved ones communicate their love languages acts of service quality time…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/five-love-languages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/five-love-languages/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;people express and receive love differently. identify how your loved ones communicate their love languages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;acts of service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quality time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;touch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;words of affirmation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mom’s been cooking a lot. that’s her preferred way of expressing love languages which is acts of service. how does she receive love? in lots of ways lol. she seems to like gifts, chatting, words of affirmation and quality time. hugs and kisses so touch. similar to others in that way… &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Emotions as an Affect Heurstic]]></title><description><![CDATA[Remember that [decision-making-length-should-be-proportional-to-importance]
emotions support this principal by helping you quickly make…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/emotions-as-an-affect-heuristic/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/emotions-as-an-affect-heuristic/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Remember that [[decision-making-length-should-be-proportional-to-importance]]
emotions support this principal by helping you quickly make decisions. Does this person piss you off? Don’t hire them. A situation feels scary? Get out of there. Intuitives hone this ability and are able to progress far in life with “gut feeling” decision making. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;creating art&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is important because people’s hearts are changed by emotion. not by logic. you don’t win people with facts. you win them with feelings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of chefs learned how to cook by brute force. Simply experimenting with different things until they discovered what tasted good guided by their intuition. This brute force nature reminds of [[interview-loop-habit-chain]] which isn’t always the wrong answer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to intuitive vs logical leaders &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;fiction’s ability to change the world vs non thinking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is to change thinking. Oftentimes art is better at this because it appeals to pathos and it’s entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another way that fiction tends to be greater than non fiction. Is the breadth that it can reach. Although I’ve argued you should favor depth over breadth many times, it’s undeniable that you reach far more people with your philsophical thoughts in a game like Nier Automata vs Thus Spoke Zarathustra. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that actually true though? Nier Automata will stay in the public conscious for maybe a decade but once it’s no longer supported it’s difficult, the graphics get too bad then the amount of people will generally stop playing it. This is somewhat difficult to judge because video games are a medium in their infancy vs the rich history of written text. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;embrace it&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;remember to feel things fully. embrace it. and then let it go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;because your emotions do lie to you. [[illusory-living]] says that emotions were a part of biological evolution as a means to propogate our genes to the next generation. useful when you are outrunning a trex.
not useful when you want to punch your boss in t he face. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Flow State]]></title><description><![CDATA[pomodoro’s for flow state pomodoro’s don’t work unless you flow state Forcing pomodoros into hour long increment forces my mentality to…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/flow-state/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/flow-state/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;pomodoro’s for flow state&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pomodoro’s don’t work unless you flow state&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forcing pomodoros into hour long increment forces my mentality to think that way. Hours are a human construct. Try 40m increments and organic break times instead of a forced ten minute break.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[During Crisis the Vulnerable are Hit Harder]]></title><description><![CDATA[This sounds obvious but I don’t see it really mentioned all that often. When a disaster hits there’s a blanket of misfortune and everyone is…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/during-crisis-the-vulnerable-are-hit-harder/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/during-crisis-the-vulnerable-are-hit-harder/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This sounds obvious but I don’t see it really mentioned all that often. When a disaster hits there’s a blanket of misfortune and everyone is worse off then they originally were. But it doesn’t apply equally. During COVID it even manifested itself as a K shape recovery. This observation is that people who were already in good positions in life did even better. Their jobs turned remote. They had space to quarantine, resources to move around. Whereas the poor suffered even worse who didn’t have those things. It’s what happened with our interns during the CQ project. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fitness]]></title><description><![CDATA[fitness prioritized goals look good naked health participate in communities focus concepts compound lifts Hits the majority of your muscles…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/fitness/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/fitness/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;fitness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;prioritized goals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look good naked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participate in communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;concepts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;compound lifts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hits the majority of your muscles, efficient&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aligns closer to &lt;strong&gt;functional strength&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;barbell lifts vs machines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;trains stabilizer muscles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more closely aligns with &lt;strong&gt;functional strength&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Counterpoint: Wouldn’t I want to do dumbell or kettlebell lifts then? A lot of bodybuilders will use smith machines to isolate muscles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;mobility - ido portal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;can you move. Ido portal’s philosophy for training. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;progressive overload&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;spinal alignment - supple leopard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posture &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;brace yourself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;warm ups and cool downs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;foam rolling (does it work) → &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/watch?v=9fvaZ_U6o3Y&amp;#x26;feature=share&quot;&gt;https://youtube.com/watch?v=9fvaZ_U6o3Y&amp;#x26;feature=share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ab work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;compound lifts do not target abs enough&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;core controls all aspects of movement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;weaknesses&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;posture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nerd neck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;workouts execution plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;warm up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;foam rolling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;core work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;strength training&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compound lifts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;accessories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ab work (core triplet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cardio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flexibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HIIT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skill Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cool down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;static stretching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Focus on One Thing at a Time]]></title><description><![CDATA[two hat theory Workflow that you are either refactoring or you are developing features. Never both at the same time.  Working memory is…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/focus-on-one-thing-at-a-time/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/focus-on-one-thing-at-a-time/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;two hat theory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workflow that you are either refactoring or you are developing features. Never both at the same time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working memory is limited and this decomposition of the problem allows you to &lt;strong&gt;focus on one thing at a time.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be applied to other freeform activities like writing or drawing. You are either writing new ideas or revising your old ones. Not both at the same time. You are either drawing roughs to get your proportions right or drawing confident nice lines. Not both at the same time. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Handling Client Integration]]></title><description><![CDATA[timeouts where is it used (client or server) renewal (keep alive vs absolute) granularity (connection level vs API level) client (low) < lb…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/handling-client-integration/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/handling-client-integration/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/ff0e5/client-integration-flow.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 42.405063291139236%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAICAYAAAD5nd/tAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAABnklEQVQoz02S0arTQBCG+/5P4Z0IBwVBxQvBC/FcaNHaqk1pk+Y0jUnTNtl0k+xmd/NJNkc5AwO7sPvNP//MjCfhHEgpqWVFtnlPtn4Dg2MYBp9jmL4n2ieswwBjDcZMqXuNdZaZKrdcNy/JgzuO6QJrISti4p+vPbCuK7JTgVId6Z8j+elCEX8hWj4nP4eUZcU+WTNY5wvOmjJmM3/FfvkWcU2RTYuoBOH8BcH9M47HgO2vBeJWsVh+psgLRLEj291T11fSLOd8vVB1AuMMM9/qk7YHY72a4Mc7otVHrFagWtxNQttOb9yAeTwjBfSKrCnojJqAqmu9AikvNG1J3dasfn8ljbYcDg/Im6CO52TxN4xzSFmRZDuvJE8CtKzIixhj9ATUSnNrb8hOID1Q8H31iXCzIEkeKC858eKOcP0Bax3WWkxvcMNAqzscgx/MOLgJqDWqU/SNwHWNvx8OIVm8pzidUEZjAAv0znjgv3RuKlCWpf83eejcuB1cREarG+/RuCX2cV1GbyotqFSF7Jv/sFGV8xZIoijifD7zFzuKYPWgeKLnAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;client integration flow&quot;
        title=&quot;client integration flow&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/f058b/client-integration-flow.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/c26ae/client-integration-flow.png 158w,
/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/6bdcf/client-integration-flow.png 315w,
/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/f058b/client-integration-flow.png 630w,
/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/40601/client-integration-flow.png 945w,
/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/78612/client-integration-flow.png 1260w,
/static/2fc90839f71104a47dcd00d7694cae24/ff0e5/client-integration-flow.png 3234w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;timeouts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;where is it used (client or server)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;renewal (keep alive vs absolute)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;granularity (connection level vs API level)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;client (low) &amp;#x3C; lb (medium) &amp;#x3C; service (highest)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;retries&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;clients need retriers !!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;network errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;throttling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;things they ask you to retry on…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;exceptions vs status codes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;failure status codes are somewhat pointless if they don’t come with an associated message. much prefer throwing exceptions instead which work with messages, metrics, and retriers&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[focus on the world around you]]></title><description><![CDATA[You can’t change the world. Not right now. Maybe not ever. You are after all, just one man. But your everyday actions have impact. On your…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/focus-on-the-world-around-you/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/focus-on-the-world-around-you/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You can’t change the world. Not right now. Maybe not ever. You are after all, just one man. But your everyday actions have impact. On your girlfriend, dogs, kids, family, coworkers, neighbors.
You impact them directly. And they impact you. And honestly. That is enough. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that you need to fix the world is pure ego. It’s clear that ever increasing scope is dooming humanity in this world. Coming from a thought process that elevates humans above all others. Destroying the Earth because of the belief that we will eventually fare space and the rest of the galaxies. That may or may not be true but the damaging effects on the world limiting the sustainability of it before we can possibly achieve those lofty goals?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local produce tastes better. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hapas and Half Elves]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stories about half elves never depict the racial identity struggles in their familial unit. Generally, the struggles they go through are…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/hapas-and-half-elves/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/hapas-and-half-elves/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Stories about half elves never depict the racial identity struggles in their familial unit. Generally, the struggles they go through are about not fitting in either side at a societal level. Their parents are always loving and supportive (or one just straight up doesn’t exist.)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Illusory Living]]></title><description><![CDATA[Humans live their life through an illusion. This is due to evolutionary biology shaping our minds not to see reality as it is but as a means…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/illusory-living/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/illusory-living/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Humans live their life through an illusion. This is due to evolutionary biology shaping our minds not to see reality as it is but as a means to propogate our genes to the next generation. This means you cannot always trust things as you see them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An Everyday Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This most often takes the form of ‘sensory’ pleasures such as junk food, promotion seeking etc. These wants motivated by the fact that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our perception of satisfaction from attaining whatever pleasure is over inflated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pleasure leaves relatively quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forces us to want the next thing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty similar to the progression of porn habits and the need for increasingly deviant behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Inbox]]></title><description><![CDATA[biases there are many biases to be aware of when you write, ponder, persuade. try to avoid (or abuse) these when going about your…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/inbox/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/inbox/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;biases&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are many biases to be aware of when you write, ponder, persuade. try to avoid (or abuse) these when going about your intellectual pursuits and knowledge work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;survivorship bias
recency bias
easily retrievable bias
abstraction bias&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;apologies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the desire to apologize comes from my desire to be forgiven rather then my desire to find peace in the individual you are apologizing to.
finding peace within yourself is fine. you should seek to do. but acknowledge that fact and don’t shroud it in the idea that you are doing so for the well being.
Practically, this means allowing that individual to be angry at you &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limit arguments to the topic at hand (don’t bring up past grievances, you had your opportunity and chose not to)
you can use them as counter examples.
Validate feelings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;social situations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yesterday I navigated two new social situations for myself. getting reamed out by a friend. and then dropping myself into a new friend group.
I’d say I had mixed success with both. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;cliques and exclusionary behavior as it relates to my team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the first one I was able to assert myself and still maintain the friendship. We still argued with eachother about some minor nuance.
Struggling with how to validate someone’s feelings.. when it just doesn’t feel like a priority. Something that is not important in my eyes… but it is important in someone else’s eyes.
Pranks wasn’t the core issue. The issue is an exclusionary.. uhh clique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clique implies a few things in my mind. Let me look up the definition tho. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a small group of people, with shared interests or other features in common, who spend time together and do not readily allow others to join them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important part is do not readily allow others to join them. Which in my mind is absolutely not true. The team is nothing but welcoming.
One fear of mine from the second social outing I had yesterday was not being allowed back into the fold if I turned down this offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But that doesn’t happen with this group. With one person who didn’t engage in shenanigans they were always invited back regardless. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;return rate of interns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;counterpoint attrition: but is that due to cultural problems or issues with management at that time period&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greater issue with cliques is making others to feel like outsiders. To not be a part of the clique is to suffer.
I don’t find it to be true either. And I wonder if there’s actual empirical envidence of this. There’s the obvious shining star of our group who does not participate in shenanigans yet is one of the most respected leaders of the team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do you draw the line between validating someone’s feelings… yet forcing them to take a look in the mirror and have a perspective shift. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So does one person’s experience indicate a trend? No. Should it be treated just as importantly?
Is there really a cultural issue? That assertion needs to be proven. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;n1 testing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group studies don’t tell you much about individuals. N1 testing as my first mentor, Jeff, liked to call it.
He also said you need to eat shit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;nutrition concepts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;favor protein&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;most food trend towards carb heavy meals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;favor vegetables&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;remember to feel things fully. embrace it. and then let it go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you don’t have a passion in life. You go from one interest to another til you die. That’s okay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;reconciling individual impact with globalization&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My individual actions mean a lot to the community around me. That’s enough.
This is stemming from my belief that focus should be given on the community around you.
Influence on a global scale might not be a good thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Romanticesize your life.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filming videos of your life is one way of doing so. By being conscious of how you would like to portray it to other people you find more clarity in your vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Capitalism : )&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalism assumes most efficient means of production is driven my human selfishness. That innovation is driven by that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe that’s true. Money is influence and insteads launches wickedness to highest power. Game theory rewards selfish behavior. Selfish individuals get to the top.  Money is influence. Power over the world. Trite statements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalism. Promotes inequality. Which stifles innovation from particular flavor of capitalism. Economics are a moving spectrum. Same with politics. It’s the sliding window of acceptable policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficient means of product was best way to prop rotate humanity. Now it’s not. Fucking the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;work effort theory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why invest yourself so much where you won’t benefit. The office theory of Jim’s and Dwights and Michaels.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;reconciling agile and long term planning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep going between mapping a year to see where you could place yourself. And then just focusing on what you are going to do this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The farther out you plan the more ambiguity there is.. with literally everything. The things I wanted a year ago aren’t the things I want now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;fitness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;do I have a spot for fitness? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep going between mapping a year to see where you could place yourself. And then just focusing on what you are going to do this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As egotistical as it is. You have to establish ethos. Social capitol before stepping out of the lines. That means actually being fit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;giving up game development&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggle to decide between what I perceive to be two artistic sides of myself. I want to acquire true master. But to do so you need focus. But a little bit of everything a day?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually you would be a savant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each day a narrative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday week a project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live your life a day at a time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I can do it all. Including art. If I specifically give up the dream of being an indie dev. I reach base level of competency over time with an hour or so dedicated to each individual activity… except game development. There’s just such breadth of specific skills you need that only apply to game development that require a base level of competency to make something anywhere near decent. I would need to sacrifice everything else. To do truly deep work. And I just can’t do that. But if I think about art. Just art. I can still manage it and live the other life I want to live. And I do want to live that life.  I’ve toyed with the idea for so long. And I know I’ll revisit it again in the future.   But for now. It’s not a path I can pursue. It’s not what makes my life worth living honestly. That’s not me talking myself out of a dream. It’s addressing all the other sides of myself that have their own wants and desires. So I’ll quiet this side of myself. For now. A good time period. I’ll grieve that side of me. And I’ll let it go. For myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the time required, what I’d need to put into it to succeed. To truly be a solo developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;fundamentals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The better your aim is. The riskier play you can make and come out on top. Lower skill players have to play differently. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;naming is hard&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in development. conveying meaning. aligning mental models. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;favor unprocessed foods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[fitness]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;follow your interests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idea proposed by smart notes that discusses organically following your interests and allowing them to build up and dictate your project plan instead of following a rigid plan from the get. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to how agile works I think? The idea being that you don’t know what customers want so you develop the most important thing now, gather feedback and then move onto the next important thing that was dictated by that feedback and the cycle begins anew. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, does this contrast with the idea of [[deep-work-habit-chain]] that proposes you spend a long time focusing on one thing at a time. Maybe not. You are performing work deeply. Just over long time periods. You’ll drop it and come back to it again. Smart notes proposes that good ideas take time to build up over the course of months or years. And that by steadily growing ideas and coming back to them organically through connections you are able to actually bring them to a satisfying conclusion. Aligns with [[habit-chain]]s as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;loki episode one&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;illusion of choice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t really follow the philosophy of the episode. He talks about hurting people. Illusion of choice. How people always make the wrong choice and hurts themselves.
Has obvious parallels to the TVA itself maintaing an illusion of choice for the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power levels are jumping based on the stone scene. where they just straight make a joke about the power stones. I generally dislike power level jumps. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Inertia of Traditions]]></title><description><![CDATA[The result of arbitrary decisions perpetuating over time by virtue of having persisting over time rather then whatever they were meant to…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/inertia-of-traditions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/inertia-of-traditions/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The result of arbitrary decisions perpetuating over time by virtue of having persisting over time rather then whatever they were meant to decide in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time changes things. Changes context. Meaning traditions that once made sense, may not make sense anymore. Understand and appreciate where these things came from, but seperate yourself from it and evaluate them for what they are. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interview Loop Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[[habit-chain]
Brute force first data structures? hash tables queues stacks data manipulations sort]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/interview-loop-habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/interview-loop-habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;[[habit-chain]]
Brute force first&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;data structures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hash tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;queues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;data manipulations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Metacognition]]></title><description><![CDATA[awareness and understanding of one’s own thought processes. structure of knowledge structure of knowledge Observation
First hand data on…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/metacognition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/metacognition/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;awareness and understanding of one’s own thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;structure of knowledge&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;structure of knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observation
First hand data on what occurs in the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpretation
What your interpretation of that data is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synthesis
What output it’s going to have on your work, thinking, lifestyle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieving Knowledge is pointless unless it has some kind of output → Collector’s fallacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How to learn&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absorb what is useful, reject what is useless, add what is essentially your own.
— Bruce Lee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[[emotions-as-an-affect-heuristic]] (the enthusiasm from a good professor, a fiction book conveying philosophy through tragic prose about human stories)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;creative projects and active engagement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a principle employed by thinking that [[writing-is-the-only-thing-that-matters]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;visuals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;exploration (testing boundaries of ideas, disagreeing with it, synthesizing it, relating to other material, derive new ideas)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one of [[the-advantages-of-videogames-as-a-medium]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;recall and spacing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spaced Repetition Systems &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chunking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;humans have limited working memory. combining information and abstracting it becomes increasingly necessary as you dive more into ecomplexity &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Diffused vs Focused Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[breaks-are-important-for-knowledge-work]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Books are ineffective Mediums for Transferring Knowledge&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much of what you read do you really remember? In order to understand something you have to actively engage with it. This is why courses are valued over just reading the source material yourself.
There’s opportunity for discourse where you synthesize against your understanding and clash with it. There’s exercises to test understanding. There’s tests that focus learning and provide an opportunity to review the material again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because they rely on “transmissionism” to convey information. author has knowledge. author writes that knowledge in a book. audience reads the book. audience gains the author’s knowledge. this is obviously not how knowledge transfer works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading by itself does not beget understanding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;rereading material over time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read an anecdote about someone who rereads The Alchemist and everytime they read it they connect with another character.
There is the new insight you’ve gained with a different perspective. But there’s also the insight gained by seeing how your thinking has evolved over time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is similar to the [[digital-constellation]]‘s principle of evolving your ideas over time. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Maintaining Personal Relationships]]></title><description><![CDATA[some of the principles I remember from that book that everyone recommends on building up your personal relationships… forgot what it’s…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/maintaining-personal-relationships/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/maintaining-personal-relationships/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;some of the principles I remember from that book that everyone recommends on building up your personal relationships… forgot what it’s called&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;use people’s names&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nicknames??? I’m not very good at those…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask for favors (people look favorably on those give favors to)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;conflict&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;validate people’s feelings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always validate the other person’s feelings. This is going to come in direct contrast with how you feel. This is why there is a conflict. You are going to resist.
Listen to them, ask questions and understand the core of what they are trying to say and not just what they explicitly say. The key word is understand. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;including your own&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because you are validating other’s feelings doesn’t mean yours aren’t valid. Remember that validating others doesn’t mean your feelings aren’t valid.
Assert yourself and [[allow-yourself-to-be-vulnerable]]. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;apologies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desire to apologize comes from my desire to be forgiven rather then my desire to find peace in the individual you are apologizing to.
finding peace within yourself is fine. you should seek to do. but acknowledge that fact and don’t shroud it in the idea that you are doing so for the other’s person well being.
Their forgiveness of you is rooted in their own emotional turmoil not your own. Allow them to come to terms with that at their own pace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially important for me and the people I happen to be close to because of the huge gulf in the time it takes to process our emotions. This is okay.
Practically, this means allowing that individual to be angry at you. Remember to let people feel emotions fully. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Limit arguments to the topic at hand&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t bring up past grievances, you had your opportunity and chose not to. Foucs on one topic at a time. Focus on the core of the issue. And that’s it. When things are resolved you can move onto other topics at hand.
You can use them as counter examples. To address similarities or draw comparisons. As a tool for helping people understand. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Making Friends Post College]]></title><description><![CDATA[a lot of people find it difficult to make friends after college. the need for human connection doesn’t go away but the easy environment…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/making-friends-post-college/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/making-friends-post-college/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;a lot of people find it difficult to make friends after college. the need for human connection doesn’t go away but the easy environment where you see the same people day after day with the same shared experiences does. For me I always wanted that core group of friends that you hang out with day after day. The kind you see in sitcoms like How I Met your Mother. I actually did have that for a bit with the boys back in Florida but life doesn’t always work out in that way. So yeah I really just want to make some cool friends out here in Seattle. I am afraid of rejection. Afraid to [[allow-yourself-to-be-vulnerable]]. Really keeps coming back to that doesn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;shared experiences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess a lot of it involves going to the same places a lot similar to why you should [[participate-in-communities]]. finding a community for the things I want to share in like art. I keep saying I need to actually have some base level competency to put myself out there in those spaces. But I guess that’s what austin was talking about when he said [[be-an-amateur]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;lead an interesting life, and invite people to it&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;let things happen organically. life doesn’t really work like that does it. live a life where you do cool stuff. invite people to do cool stuff. Again I never want to invite people to do things. Like why would this person want to hang out with me lol. Ah well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cool stuff I want to try around here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vanmoof&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Keystone Habits]]></title><description><![CDATA[the first additive habits or focus areas you should focus on when attempting to change your life.
don’t forget to take your MEDS Meditation…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/keystone-habits/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/keystone-habits/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;the first additive habits or focus areas you should focus on when attempting to change your life.
don’t forget to take your MEDS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it’s taking care of your body and mind. self care. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Counterpoint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;are so much more important then anything else. if you aren’t healthy then everything else suffers. yet this isn’t entirely true. this isn’t what energizes me. doing this work right here. these morning papers. these mixing of ideas. this is what energizes me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not only that but I see people with the absolute WORST health habits. eating terribly. so how are these people able to operate? people are different I guess. I defintely need to be in tune with all my habits in order to operate effectively. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Have Respect for Yourself]]></title><description><![CDATA[this is the speech I wrote after a friend had yelled at me at work. this realization of having low self worth is rooted in the same idea as…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/have-respect-for-yourself/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/have-respect-for-yourself/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;this is the speech I wrote after a friend had yelled at me at work. this realization of having low self worth is rooted in the same idea as [[allow-yourself-to-be-vulnerable]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that I am not worth it. But I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;speech to yourself and to others&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It bothered me for a while and I was struggling to figure out why. And it did bother me. I took off work and didn’t do anything for the rest of the day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please correct me if I have the wrong impression. You are my friend. Smart driven funny individual. Want to hang out with you on the weekend. I respect you.  And what being a friend really means to me more then anything else is I care about what you have to say. If a homeless guy says you suck I wouldn’t care. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your defensive statement that it was for the room and not directed at me made it worse in my mind. And that made it clear. Because Speaking to other people that way isn’t okay and that is obvious. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realized I didn’t apply the same standard to myself. I need to have respect for myself. I will not be scolded like a child. I’m an adult. A human being. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But P.E. talks to people including me that way and I don’t care. Cuz he’s my coworker not my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be coworkers. That’s fine.  No worries and I’ll treat you with respect no matter what. I honestly am going to act pretty similar at work regardless. I just won’t really care what you have to say about me and I won’t inject in your personal affairs either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but I won’t be spoken to that way by a friend. Cuz I won’t care about what they have to say.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Personal Aesthetic]]></title><description><![CDATA[abg I’ve been seeing this visual trend a lot and I kind of want to emulate a male version of it. A lot of the aesthetics are really cool. I…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/my-personal-aesthetic/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/my-personal-aesthetic/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;abg&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been seeing this visual trend a lot and I kind of want to emulate a male version of it. A lot of the aesthetics are really cool. I am also probably misattributing characteristics that don’t define an ABG but it’s just a general inspiration for me and not necessarilly a 1:1 of what I want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;statement pieces&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is okay. Not every piece of your wardrobe should be a statement piece. The rest of your outfit is meant to complement that statement piece. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;list of things I like : )&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;delicate floral tattoos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bleach blond hair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;colored contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;earthy toned clothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aesthetic fitness &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DANGLY MF EARRINGS &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They tend to dress less conservatively but not sure how to emulate that as a male!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also really love long flowing cardigans and jackets. I already have a few of them. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;athletic fit shirts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high waisted pants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white leather shoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;everlane the cotton crew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asrv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;base layers conveying a masculine|athletic frame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chains, earrings, accessories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;diversity in your space&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one big reason I am drawn so much to this aesthetic is because a lot of it runs counter to normal aesthetics that developers tend to prefer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minimalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black, white neutral tones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RBG (saturated colors and lights)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there’s [[inherent-value-in-diversity]] and introducing other aesthetics to the scene creates diversity for others but also makes you stand out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;otter mode&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if I think about my ideal body types they generally aren’t that big. they’re straight otter mode. and that involves cutting. god damn rena and her love for food but not eating that much of it. that tiktok about how boyfriends get fat is so true. “babe I’m full” anyways I need to cut calories. no more drinking calories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;be like the sun&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always told dylan that he is the sun. Just a big bright ball of energy that gives life and energy to everyone around him. I’ve always admired that about him. I’ve never had such flowery allegories for myself for others but for him it’s just so clear and crystalized in my mind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m more cold. Demure. Probably we I have an attaction to cooler pale tones that don’t stand out. But is that how I want to be? I’m not sure. I feel myself always striving in social situations but what for. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[N1 Testing]]></title><description><![CDATA[Group studies don’t tell you much about individuals. N1 testing as my first mentor, Jeff, liked to call it is what you should be doing. IE…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/n1-testing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/n1-testing/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Group studies don’t tell you much about individuals. N1 testing as my first mentor, Jeff, liked to call it is what you should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IE you should just experiment with things to see what works for you. Similar to Rena’s philosophy on [[skincare-is-selfcare]] that you should just try things and see if they work. Skin has such variability that whatever works for other people with similar skin types might not work for you. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reaper Characters]]></title><description><![CDATA[[eji] [sei] keshi a soft reaper. one whom you may have to execute. affinity for birds?
has light loose rope like chains around his neck…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/reaper-characters/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/reaper-characters/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[eji]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[sei]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;keshi&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a soft reaper. one whom you may have to execute. affinity for birds?
has light loose rope like chains around his neck.
you don’t want to have to fight him. a cerebral character. when you eventually &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ava&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has a choker &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Minimize Regret]]></title><description><![CDATA[One of Jeff Bezo’s mental models for decision making. Think about yourself on your death bed and think about what you’d regret more and that…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/minimize-regret/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/minimize-regret/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;One of Jeff Bezo’s mental models for decision making. Think about yourself on your death bed and think about what you’d regret more and that will guide your choice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concept I wanted to explore for [[reaper]]. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Participate in Communities]]></title><description><![CDATA[don’t be a lurker!
show up the same place everyday and you make friends. this supports [favor-depth-of-experience-over-breadth] why provides…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/participate-in-communities/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/participate-in-communities/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;don’t be a lurker!
show up the same place everyday and you make friends. this supports [[favor-depth-of-experience-over-breadth]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;why&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provides another input source for creative inspiration and ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connections for your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more then anything it’s just refreshing. people are biologically hardwired to need social connections. so do you. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;form quality (not quantity) connections&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it doesn’t matter if you have a million vapid surface level friends. but if you have a few that you truly connect with, then that means the world.
you’ve always wanted a core friend group. forming those relationships by [[favor-depth-of-experience-over-breadth]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;scenius&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;great ideas are often birthed by a group of creative individuals—artists, curators, thinkers, theorists, and other tastemakers—who make up an “ecology of talent.”
the best creative geniuses were often part of a whole scene of people who were supporting each other, stealing ideas, and contributing ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;for your own self satisfaction and standing on the shoulders of giants&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember having this discussion with Tucker a while back. About how you should give back to communities. Basically I said that you should participate in communities. Give back. Because this actually increases your own feelings of happiness and contentness. But that’s not why you should do it. You should do it because of everything society has given to you up to this point. The collective altruism, determination, and engenuity of humankind throughout our history all allowing you to live the life that you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This flies in the face of [[you-did-not-consent-to-this-life]]. Why should you have these obligations to a life you never asked to be a part of. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kleon, Austin - Show your Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[No title]]></title><description><![CDATA[reaper characters [reaper-characters] battle system mental battles I really liked the idea of multiple viewpoints existing in your head with…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/reaper/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/reaper/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;reaper&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;characters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[reaper-characters]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;battle system&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;mental battles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked the idea of multiple viewpoints existing in your head with Disco Elysium. One way I see this playing out in Reaper is letting emotions build up and unleashing them in attacks. This is where the visuals come into play. The allegory is letting your emotions out vs bottling them up. Expressing yourself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;attacks are different ways of manipulating emotions. making them pissed off. calming yourself down. then you can attack out of anger, alleviating yourself of that emotion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in traditional fights you will invade their mind directly and do a few things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assess how they’re feeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search for weak points &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manipulate their emotions (make them angry, hit harder but less accurately)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;good jrpg battles force you to make hard decisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;physical battles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then in real life you fight normally using an ATB system. real time action builds up an action bar where you enter their mind and inflict hell upon them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;finally to execute them you have to swipe across their neck. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;your first reaper battles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;one day your target doesn’t have too many descriptors. but one noticeable one is they have a lengthy coat which sei notices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;during the battle he will invade both your minds. sei will have depressing thoughts. it doesn’t matter. if we die we die. eji will attempt to rouse himself out more positively. I can do this. don’t let her get to you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this reaper, keshi, is someone you’ll commonly have interactions with throughout the game. maybe they’ll be like eji. someone who cares too much. is too passionate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eji struggles with mental battles but this represents a necessary turning point for him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is alluded to, that something like this happens and reapers can be targets until the midway battle when a reaper assaults your mind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;boss fights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the inspiration for boss fights are like the waves of emotion. you hold it in until the breaking point. then it breaks and unleashes. similar to phases in a boss fight. in this game subsequent waves get a bit easier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it comes in waves. emotions. you have to pass thresh holds and then things come crashing down all over you. like activating the next phase in a boss fight. the stages of grief
denial -&gt; acceptance &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;lore&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;reaper origins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reapers are those with regrets but have controlled their feelings.
when you become a reaper you forget the reason you feel the way you do.
all you have left are your emotions but you don’t remember why.
eventually when your “responsibilities are absolved” so are your emotions and thus your regret.&lt;br&gt;
responsibilities being an allegory for passion or pupose in life.
there’s no more reason left to live. but are they being absolved?
or is it just being left to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;love plant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a plant that you can only own one of. Try to own anymore and the old plant eventually withers away and dies. Many attempts have been made by owners to try and own more than one but eventually only one remains in the end. Life restoration plant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;plot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the missions play out relatively the same. it starts out with them just chatting at a coffee shop. discussing philosophy or whatever. they get texted their mission and then they’re off. it’s relatively hub based? it takes place in a big city so things are cramped.
it’s a spirit city though… so cars and people aren’t there (so I don’t have to draw them)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reaper explores the question how do you live a life without regrets… how do you [[minimize-regret]]
each day explores a different facet of that question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;mission 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the first mission sees eji chasing something. running through an alleyway and get obscured by some buildings. camera pans up to the sky where sei is smoking. his smoke flows through the sky. r e a p e r appears over the moon. fades out.  fades back to eji. you fight some monsters. you fight a remixed monster that forces you to change your tactics. you fight a combination of both. you fight a boss that tests your understanding of the remix. but then there’s a barrier. they’re too resistent. that is when sei comes in and invades their mind. afterwords a small amount of exposition. the next day starts at the coffee shop where they chat until the target text comes in. and then they’re off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;mission 2 - I should’ve done more with my life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regret doing the risky thing vs the not risky thing. I should’ve joined that startup and followed my dream. instead I worked for megaco and died a slave. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sei: I remember that company… it never even took off.
eji: It’s not about whether it took off. It’s about doing it. Knowing that you gave it your all..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;like PT but instead of a traditional horror it’s more of a surrealist existential horror. I’m going to do the same everything, everyday for the rest of my life until I die. is this what life is? you repeatedly go down the same hallway fighting the same enemies
go through their life. at the end is the boss.. the regret on their death bed. each time you go through the hallway you have to figure out how it’s changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;mission 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eji isn’t allowed in the room during the discussion on what to do about a certain spirit.
They go to execute the soft spirit. But he seems to be in control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;another antagonistic reaper is your physical partner when you eventually take down sei.
she openly yearns for the day she can take down sei. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;mission 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the game ends with you taking down sei. sei’s story is one of nihilism. you can do everything right. live a virtuous life. have the right amount of fun. find the perfect partner. but still leave life feeling like it wasn’t enough. sei’s mind wouldn’t let him be happy. yet he still hoped. trying to rouse him positively is almost impossible. you have to appeal to his nihilism. this life. everything in it. wasn’t worth it. nothing is. arms come from the ground. each one and arrow through his heart. and drags him into the ground until there’s nothing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;concepts for enemies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;enemies are manifestations of regret or strong feelings left behind before they died. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;someone who’s killed themselves but stayed behind. they wanted to end it all but they felt strongly enough that they stayed behind. a life without &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;reaper artstyle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;artstyle can be a mix like omori. pixel art 2d overworld. hand drawn battle system. look to manhwas for character design. I really like the girl from that one bdsm manga. I want to model the antagonistic shinigami after her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;game takes place across a city that slowly opens up as it progresses and as it opens up it lets you revist areas you’ve already been to. similar to TWEWY. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;in game assets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vending machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;artificial recreations of nature is a theme I like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aquarium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green house&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plant shop &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;concept art pieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;title &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coffee shop hang out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shops to buy items &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vending machine screen (reflects you and sei)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;character art&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reapers have a few common traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;long trailing pieces of clothing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;neck pieces to protect ya neck against other reapers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;random&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you can’t. Sei’s philosophy is you can’t. Accept your despair. Accept that nothing could have been done. Eji is you can try. Strive. Leave it to the next generation. Nihilism. eji is naive though. I’ll do what I want. Idealistic. Sei is practical. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you still live a life of regrets anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(what was this conversation even about.. I forgot)
eji - I mean it’s not even about the fame at that point. like why even perform if only five dudes are going to listen.
sei - because those five dudes understand. and that’s all that matters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;enemies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always struggle with lore and designs for enemies. It has just never resonated that much to me. I’m always imagining the heroes in my mind but never the grunts that you face. It’s rare that I even think too much about them actually. Omori enemies were a bit bland but had random moments of personality. Undertale enemies were good and memorable. I think I should strive for that. Screens should be a mix of story, a few forced enemies, maybe some minor exploration and puzzle solving. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Seek Work That Energizes You]]></title><description><![CDATA[please put on your mask before attempting to help others with their mask Jeff Bezo’s Work Life Harmony This contrasts with work life balance…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/seek-work-that-energizes-you/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/seek-work-that-energizes-you/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;please put on your mask before attempting to help others with their mask&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Jeff Bezo’s Work Life Harmony&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This contrasts with work life balance that concludes energy to be a zero sum game. The more you invest in work then less you invest in life. Instead work life harmony touts that you should strive for a life where your work gives you energy and your life gives you energy. They feed into eachother supplying each side with energy and forming the virtuous cycle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Energy vampires&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people in life that add energy in the room. And there are people in life who take it away. Strive to be like the first example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;As opposed to focusing on impact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impact is a company centric approach whereas energy is a person centric approach. This aligns with the idea that you should better yourself and that inevitably makes the company better. Also aligns with the idea of scaling down focus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conflict with Grit?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s something to be said about grit though. Facing adversity head on and getting through it. Is that sustainable. This talks about sustaining high output overtime for pratically the rest of your life. When you think about those incredible acts of determintion generally they are during the pivotal moments. Crunch time is something that happens the weekend before launch. Not every single weekend for your entire life. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Priorities for Different Level of Software Developer]]></title><description><![CDATA[SDE III Should have project level visibility roles guiding devs high ambiguity force multiplication
SDE II Should have work stream level…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/priorities-for-different-level-of-developer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/priorities-for-different-level-of-developer/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;SDE III Should have project level visibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;roles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guiding devs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high ambiguity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;force multiplication
SDE II Should have work stream level visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;individual contribution
SDE I should have task level visibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pareto principle]]></title><description><![CDATA[-
focus on the things that matter. there will be things that have an outsized impact on any project that you do. find those things and do…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/pareto-principle/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/pareto-principle/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;-
focus on the things that matter. there will be things that have an outsized impact on any project that you do. find those things and do them first. this applies to almost every facet of life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are changes you can make to your life that will have an outsized impact. these are your [[keystone-habits]]&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Skincare is selfcare]]></title><description><![CDATA[skincare-is-selfcare Cologne everyday - studies show that you are more confident when you wear cologne. this translates even through photos…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/skincare-is-selfcare/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/skincare-is-selfcare/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;skincare-is-selfcare&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cologne everyday - studies show that you are more confident when you wear cologne. this translates even through photos
Less shampoo - we generally use too much cleanser in every aspect of our lives
Colder shorter showers - better for your skin than hot long showers
Scentless - conflicts with cologne and skincare
Shave every other day - I can’t grow a suitable mustache unfortunately. Just keep yourself trim&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[sei]]></title><description><![CDATA[sei is measured, composed. relaxed. flexibile.  wears a necklace with a simple chain and an ornate pendant. 
sei’s necklace pendant (a…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/sei/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/sei/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;sei is measured, composed. relaxed. flexibile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wears a necklace with a simple chain and an ornate pendant.
sei’s necklace pendant (a signature piece) becomes a dangly earring that eji wears after their battle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sei doesn’t have a scythe (or equivilent weapon). you don’t need it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sei’s backstory is a lost love. he lived a good life. stoic mindset. they both died together. (or he died first and she found a new love) he waited for her but she never showed up. he waited for a long time. eventually he naturally forgot why he felt the way he did. one day someone offered him a coat and a job. he’s someone who takes his responsibilities seriously. does the adult job. his story is that sometimes it doesn’t matter. sometimes you’ll just die full of regret. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sei is a reluctant mentor. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Research Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[[habit-chain] create expectation read chapter summarize chapter relate to overall summary summarize book convert to smart notes mental…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/research-habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/research-habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;[[habit-chain]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create expectation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;summarize chapter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relate to overall summary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;summarize book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;convert to smart notes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mental models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;process changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;idea extensions, questions, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sacrifice your Unique Vision for Impact]]></title><description><![CDATA[a leader has two qualities a strong idea of what the world ought to be like and the desire to make it so having this vision and aligning…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/sacrifice-your-unique-vision-for-impact/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/sacrifice-your-unique-vision-for-impact/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;a leader has two qualities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a strong idea of what the world ought to be like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the desire to make it so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;having this vision and aligning others around you means you can achieves so much more than you could have as an individual. but eventually that hits a ceiling. your ability to align everyone under your singular vision reaches it’s limit. I’m not sure where or how it happens but it does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after that you have a choice. you can trade your unique vision for a bigger impact. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;going up the management chain in a mega conglomerate means working with other leaders who each have a equally strong vision. aligning with others means you have clash, align and make common ground with other world views. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; each individual voice is lost in a sea of others but there’s some guiding vision. some shared worldview all pushing us in the same direction? enacting an enormous prescence on the world. that’s what you get for sacrificing your unique voice. is it worth it? is it something to emulate for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;software projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the difficultly from writing large software projects isn’t in writing lines of code. that’s the easy part and anyone can do that. but it’s from aligning a team’s vision and mental models. if everyone could share the same mind and understand things exactly the same then development projects could infinitely scale up. however the exponential increase in  communication channels and linear increase in  conflicting mental models|world views means that you see a decrease in productivity as you add developers to a project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;as it applies to myself&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;solo game development vs finding a team. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;auters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;todo: people with such strength of vision, renaissance man who can directly control all aspects of a project that involes multiple people. think hideo kojima. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sprint Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[generic workflow for how I approach projects levels at the beginning of each level, design down until you have the next level sufficient for…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/sprint-habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/sprint-habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;generic workflow for how I approach projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;levels&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;at the beginning of each level, design down until you have the next level sufficient for you to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;projects (however long)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sprints (1-2 weeks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dailies (1day)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pomodoros(1hr)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;sprint&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[habit-chain]] for defining a sprint&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;raw ideation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;define current state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;define SMART goal &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cut scope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;define TTT and space and communities required to succeed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;techniques &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;theories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;space and communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;daily work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;synthesis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compilation (compile research into og notes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[design-habit-chain]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decision making &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mechanical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this shouldn’t require a lot of thinking or decision making. you should be able to listen to music &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;documentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exocortex (generic notes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project management &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;research &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;targeted research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;books (async)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;post sprint (output)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;social media (youtube, demo)  → curate a story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;routine shift → workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Social Capital]]></title><description><![CDATA[Actually I think this is more commonly reffered to as SMV on online dating forums.]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/social-capital/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/social-capital/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Actually I think this is more commonly reffered to as SMV on online dating forums.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Software Engineer Manager Conversations]]></title><description><![CDATA[wins, flex, goal progression past, present, future Topic Ideas Forward Looking Conversations like Roadmap, Team Direction, Something missing…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/software-engineer-manager-conversations/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/software-engineer-manager-conversations/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wins, flex, goal progression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;past, present, future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Topic Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forward Looking Conversations like Roadmap, Team Direction, Something missing attention or focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what they are focused on, Right now that’s CQ Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Process Improvements, OE, Knowledge Transfers &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oncall is bad, how can we improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer Stress Happiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer stress/happiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What work is being planned (We’ve been discussing Siri/HomePod integration getting cut recently)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections results (although I don’t see those very often, so we don’t discuss this too often)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Software Architect]]></title><description><![CDATA[considerations when designing industry standard unless you have a reason not to software architect’s role minimize effort to build and…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/software-architect/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/software-architect/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;considerations when designing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;industry standard unless you have a reason not to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;software architect’s role&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minimize effort to build and maintain software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;predict and allow for change (software changes over it’s lifetime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defend the architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;goals for architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use cases → architecture screams it’s purpose, it is clearly what it’s intended to portray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;operation → can handle hardware operations and future ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;development → architecture often reflects organizational structure. this is to faciliate multiple teams working independently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deployment →deployed right after being built&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Foundations of Architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between good and bad architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintainability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resources required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;customer trust, manager wrath, team morale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;effort to change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Architecture Requirements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;reliability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;work through faults (hardware, human, software)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;scalability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;load → TPS, read/write, throughput
performance →&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how it degrades with increased load and resources kept the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how it stays the same with increased load and resources increased&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;maintainability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;operability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evolvability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;volatility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is most likely to change?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how do you allow for it &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Systems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. clean architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their general plan for a clean architecture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependency Rule → source code dependencies must point only inward, towards higher lvl policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code is separated into four layers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface adapters (controllers presenters adapters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frameworks and tools (web ui db devices)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. create plugin architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;layers, especially lower ones should be hot swappable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Service&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dependency Injection &gt; Hard Coding Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flexibility → Use different resources
Testability → Easier Mocking
Reusability → More generic components&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Package Organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizontal - Doesn’t scream architecture.. looks like anything else
Vertical - Leaves Potentential to skip layers
Component - persistence and business logic are combined&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Separation of Concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Object orientated Programming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functional Programming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Data Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structural Programming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Screaming architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your architecture should plainly state its use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the framework. Not the database. Not the delivery system. It should be about the use cases. You should be able to defer those decisions.  Someone should be able to look at the source and base directory and immediately say oh this is an rpg or this is a an inventory system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testable without knowledge of database or delivery system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Defining Partial Partial Boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an architect you are often going to run into [[you-are-not-going-to-need-it]] But it’s your job to think… I might need it. This need evolves overtime and with business needs.
Restrict volatility on things that don’t matter. This is where experience comes in handy. You can tell what doesn’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design a service as if they were two. But deploy them in the same package. That way you can easily separate. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One way boundaries. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facades → A client calls a class which just serves to call other classes that the client never has access to. There’s still a transitive dependency however though. The boundary is very weak. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Component (Package) Cohesion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three Guiding Principles (They push and pull against each other)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCP → Group things that are likely to change at the same time for same reason&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRP → split classes that will make callers depend on things they don’t need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REP → granule of reuse is the same as granule of release&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;data decisions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective data models are not even slightly clever - Will Larson (Staff Engineer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you focusing on transactions or analytics on your data?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at your encoded data (data in transition, through network or saved to state like json, and xml) focus on evolvability. Is it backwards and fowards compatible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old application code can accidentally overwrite database properties it doesn’t recognize if it just ignores them!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;intrinsic vs extrinsic properties&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when you think about data are properties intrinsic or extrinsic
is it core to the object or external&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;example
intrisic, car is red, couple, fast
extrinsic, car’s owner, location&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Class&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SOLID Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single Responsibility Principle - classes should change only because of one actor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Closed Principle - classes should be open to addition… not to modification&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liskov Substitution Principle - Things should be substituble without worry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interface Segragation Principle - don’t combine things people don’t need&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependency Inversion Principle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t rely on concrete implementations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t derive from concrete implementations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t override concrete functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t mention name of anything concrete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;technical writing design documents&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;the base formula&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;general tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emphasize clarity of thought and substance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid weasel words and passive action (use active verbs instead) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[allow-yourself-to-be-vulnerable]] and assert yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead w/ proposal and then lead through journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualizations are great like sequence diagrams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;sample six pager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Cases → Tech Requirements → Key Tech Decisions → Approaches → Trade offs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use to narrow scope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emphasize BRD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create functional requirements (intrinsic requirements)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional Constraints including current state of world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenants &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;used to guide decision points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementation Plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appendices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Strive for Ideals, Operate Practically]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s a huge gap between how society should operate and what it currently is. This is going to be true at any stage of development…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/strive-for-ideals-operate-practically/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/strive-for-ideals-operate-practically/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s a huge gap between how society should operate and what it currently is. This is going to be true at any stage of development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philosophy, generallities should be discussed in a vacuum. Can strive for perfection. But when you attempt to apply these ideals to reall life, context is required and sometimes an ideal cannot be reached. It needs to be balanced with time as a resource. What we can do now to push us towards that ideal but address all the issues at hand.  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stoicism vs Epicureanism]]></title><description><![CDATA[restraining yourself from all spectrum of emotion like pleasure because you believe that it somehow makes you more stoic is the opposite of…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/stoicism-vs-epicureanism/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/stoicism-vs-epicureanism/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;restraining yourself from all spectrum of emotion like pleasure because you believe that it somehow makes you more stoic is the opposite of stoic. partake in carnal pleasures  but do not let them control you. if that’s not possible, recognize your limits as such. but for that reason and not a belief that not engaging in all life has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is incredibly common in software engineering where people tend to idolize “logical” robotic ways of decision making and carrying yourself unaware of the fact that the implicit biases in their thought patterns trend them towards certain routes anyways. ignore the role of [[emotions-as-an-affect-heuristic]] to guide decision making. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Software Engineer Interview Questions]]></title><description><![CDATA[interviewer name, role, time w/ company company total employees?
split between QA and Dev and OPS 
business model? office what percentage of…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/software-engineer-interview-questions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/software-engineer-interview-questions/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;interviewer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;name, role, time w/ company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;company&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;total employees?
split between QA and Dev and OPS
business model?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;office&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what percentage of staff is remote?
what drove this decision?
does compensation change based on location?
open office? location?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;happiness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what’s motivating?
what’s frustrating?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what needs are trying to be fulfilled?
tech stack?
time for attacking tech debt? experimentation? meetings?
Have you made any recent changes to your development process?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;deadlines, tasking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;who decides what gets worked on?
how much influence do engineers have?
how much autonomy do they have?
who creates deadlines?
what kind of pressure is backing deadlines?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;learning resources?
food/snacks?
office or remote perks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;professional development?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you were looking for a job last time, what made you choose this company?
mentorship?
events, conferences, hackathons?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[There is an Overwhelming Amount of Information in the World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Print → Persistent
Phone → Instant
Internet → Persistent and Instant
This has resulted in an overflow of knowlege, more than anyone can hope…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/there-is-an-overwhelming-amount-of-information-in-the-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/there-is-an-overwhelming-amount-of-information-in-the-world/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Print → Persistent
Phone → Instant
Internet → Persistent and Instant
This has resulted in an overflow of knowlege, more than anyone can hope to contain in a lifetime.
This has a few implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first is the creation of the [[attention-economy]] and how that becomes your most important resource. Social media’s goal is to drain that resource from you, that’s their currency. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the next avenue for the progression of knowledge is filtering out what’s relevant, true (fake news) and how we experience that knowledge (Oculus, virtual reality). curating your input streams becomes incredibly important so you can [[favor-depth-of-experience-over-breadth]]. Biasing towards long form media is helpful because it implicitly filters out vapid, low thoughts that and common with low barriers of entry for sharing information online. The skill in your mind to forget things is called active inhibition. It’s important to be able to forget because your mind would be overwhelmed with experiences otherwise. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Staff Engineer]]></title><description><![CDATA[Encompasses the highest levels of the individual contributor track for an engineer’s career. Has a noticeable jump in ambiguity between…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/staff-engineer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/staff-engineer/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Encompasses the highest levels of the individual contributor track for an engineer’s career. Has a noticeable jump in ambiguity between staff and senior. Not in the level of ambiguity in the problems you face, although it does increase but the level of ambiguity in job responsibilities as well. The breadth of responsibilities is wide enough that individuals tend to find themselves falling into pretty common archetypes of staff engineer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tech lead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;architect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;right hand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problem solver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;sponsorship vs mentorship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mentorship is giving advice, sponsorship is giving opportunities.
oftentimes opportunies are what is needed not advice. your mentorship time can be used to explore your mentee’s interests, talents, to help inform your sponsorship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://larahogan.me/blog/what-sponsorship-looks-like/&quot;&gt;Lara Hogan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;being glue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘glue work’ is work required to make the project succeed but falls outside the realm of ‘promotable’ work. it’s expected when you are a staff engineer but detrimental when you aren’t. be conscious of how much voluntary, non-promotable work you are doing and focus on the core skills you want to be developing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;although it’s essential to becoming a staff engineer, it’s not the focus I want to have right now. I need to pare down as many meetings I have as possible (or group them actually)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://noidea.dog/glue&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tanya Reilly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;[[continously-iterate-on-technical-quality]]&lt;/h2&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Test Driven Development]]></title><description><![CDATA[Methods Fake it (stub implementations) obvious implementation The reason to articulate it this way is that if you ever get blown away by…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/test-driven-development/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/test-driven-development/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Methods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fake it (stub implementations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;obvious implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason to articulate it this way is that if you ever get blown away by 2, you can always fall back to 1 and KEEP MOVING.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Three Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write failing test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write code to make test pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactor mothafucka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Iterative Speed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;json&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;brazil-build single-integration-test -DtestClass=&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;com.amazon.amazonmusicqueueserviceecs.activity.addtoqueue.AddToQueueBoundaryTest&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

brazil-build debug-single-integration-test -DtestClass=&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;com.amazon.amazonmusicqueueserviceecs.activity.addtoqueue.AddToQueueBoundaryTest&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

bb | grep ✘&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;brazil-build debug-single-integration-test -DtestClass=“com.amazon.amazonmusicqueueserviceecs.activity.setshuffle.SetShuffleOrchestratorTest”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t depend on anything volatile like guis or services - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/Clean-Architecture-f3a58bdb34d84a3d91c344a45ad7ccc4&quot;&gt;Clean Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Structural coupling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test for every production class and method
Tests are strongly coupled to production.
Prevents refactoring and makes code rigid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;humble data pattern&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At architecture boundaries a humble data pattern will often exists. It basically divides classes into easy and hard to test division. Something like data conversions from services or databases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;captors&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;use in place of any() being passed into mocks
it captures any input being passed into the mock
and then you can assert on what you expect the input to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-java&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token annotation punctuation&quot;&gt;@Captor&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;ArgumentCaptor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token generics&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;IReportDevicePlaybackResponse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; responseCaptor&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;when&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;reportDevicePlaybackResponseConverter&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;convert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;responseCaptor&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;capture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;thenReturn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;externalResponse&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;assertEquals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;response&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; responseCaptor&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;getValue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;potential issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make sure you verify values are called AFTER the subject method is actually ran…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tenets]]></title><description><![CDATA[tenets need to guide [decision-making]. when there’s a tradeoff between two competing goals then a tenet is required  life tenets “you have…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/tenets/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/tenets/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;tenets need to guide [[decision-making]]. when there’s a tradeoff between two competing goals then a tenet is required &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;life tenets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“you have to start romanticizing your life”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[[keystone-habits]] &gt; Events &gt; Project Work &gt; Actual Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The counterpoint is that your actual work will have the most outsized impact on your life. The effort I gave into leetcoding and succeeding in my job gave me the literal capitol I required in order to get my other affairs in order and help Rena live a better life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;minimalism tenets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you should never be able to say “I forgot I had this”. What’s the point of having it then. Either discard it or place it somewhere where you will be able to get it when you need it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your posessions should ‘spark joy’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus on what matters (essentialism), not having less&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Importance of Family meals]]></title><description><![CDATA[the worst things in life are being alone and hungry so make sure to always cherish meals with loved ones. deeply cultural
food is the only…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/the-importance-of-family-meals/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/the-importance-of-family-meals/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the worst things in life are being alone and hungry so make sure to always cherish meals with loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;deeply cultural
food is the only experience utilized by all five senses. besides sex?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;truly tasting your food&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[focus-on-one-thing-at-a-time]] and actually taste what you are eating. how many times have you gone through a meal and not really tasted what you are eating. eating with loved ones is one of the only things you can do while eating whilst still enjoying the meal. there’s down periods of chatting where you can truly focus on what you are eating&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Video Game Ideas]]></title><description><![CDATA[During one meeting my art director passed me a sticky note covered in drawings of cats. Dozens. He was gone within a week and all that was…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/video-game-ideas/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/video-game-ideas/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;During one meeting my art director passed me&lt;/em&gt; a &lt;em&gt;sticky note covered&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;em&gt;drawings&lt;/em&gt; of &lt;em&gt;cats&lt;/em&gt;. Dozens. He was gone &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; a week and all that was left was &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A sea that never settles.&lt;/em&gt; for as long as anyone can remember this part of the sea has always been stormy. not anymore dangerous than the storm implies but a mystery as to why it always seems to be rough waters in this are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;A gift of beads.&lt;/em&gt; For every kill he added a bead. blah blah different type of kill added a different bead to the jar. on my birthday he gave me a necklace made out of the beads. looked at myself in the mirror and touched every single bead on there. that night I ran away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System for managing resources. Ingredients get delivered. Fresh ones go bad. You have to preserve which lowers their usefulness or changes it.  Some rare ingredients to bad after a day. You concoct potions from them. Rarer potions require a bunch of rare items delivered at once. You can supplement buy buying specialty ingredients but it’s expensive. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Writing is the Only Thing that Matters]]></title><description><![CDATA[Living this way doesn’t mean that the way you spend your time is different. It means the way you think during that time is different…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/writing-is-the-only-thing-that-matters/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/writing-is-the-only-thing-that-matters/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Living this way doesn’t mean that the way you spend your time is different. It means the way you think during that time is different. Everything becomes deliberate. If you read to write. Then you read to understand.
If I eat to cook. I understand more.
If I read designs to develop. Then I understand. It informs thinking.  So you keep gaming. You keep watching. Because it informs creation. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Weekend Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[friday spa night [habit-chain] bath candles exfoliate body with towel and ocean salt exfoliate face with foreo? face roller facemask full…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/weekend-habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/weekend-habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;friday spa night [[habit-chain]]&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;candles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exfoliate body with towel and ocean salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exfoliate face with foreo?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;face roller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facemask&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;full body massage &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;park walk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cheat meal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anime!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;saturdates and social media habit chain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;morning: chores &amp;#x26; meal prep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;afternoon: events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: social media editing (vlog editing, instagram posts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;sundaze project prep habit chain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;morning: project research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;afternoon: review and project planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;life review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;project initiation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;raw ideation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inspiration gathering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;week planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;film talking head intro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: excess exocortex tending and social media &lt;strong&gt;planning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[No title]]></title><description><![CDATA[my nihillistic (probably other’s) idea that you never consented to be born. Any expectation for you is nil because of this.  You shouldn’t…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/you-did-not-consent-to-this-life/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/you-did-not-consent-to-this-life/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;my nihillistic (probably other’s) idea that you never consented to be born. Any expectation for you is nil because of this.  You shouldn’t HAVE to do anything because you didn’t ask to be born. You’ve now been given all these obligations. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[YAGNI]]></title><description><![CDATA[An engineering principal meant to prevent overengineering a code base. The idea that you don’t need to write code anticipating future use…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/you-are-not-going-to-need-it/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/you-are-not-going-to-need-it/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;An engineering principal meant to prevent overengineering a code base. The idea that you don’t need to write code anticipating future use cases. Sometimes you don’t need a strategy pattern. Sometimes you just need an if statement. Could be a good life philosophy as well lol.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;counterpoint is a good software architect should be able to identify volatility aka the times you are in fact going to need it. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Your Work Does not Speak for Itself]]></title><description><![CDATA[emotions and feelings are critical to conveying things, especially as an artist. the context around something provides a frame for how your…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/your-work-does-not-speak-for-itself/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/your-work-does-not-speak-for-itself/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;emotions and feelings are critical to conveying things, especially as an artist. the context around something provides a frame for how your audience should view your piece. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this includes the idea of seperating art from the artist. they are inexplicably tied. it’s why ethos is one of pillars of persuasian. the context provides another way to hook people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it something Smart Notes mentioned in the academic world. That an idea exists in a vacuum. Once the pen hits the paper it doesn’t matter what you meant. What matters is what you wrote. My mind can’t help but go back to the Doctor who proposed the 24 hour oncall and how he’d regularly use cocaine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Necessary to participate in society and why that doesn’t make you a hypocrite&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the classic example for this is someone with left leaning economic idealogy participating in capitalistic behavior. How can someone who claims to support those kinds of policies actively engage in behavior antithecal to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason is I need to live motherfucker. Being thrust into this society inherently means you have to engage with it on some level. That means playing according to the rules until you can come out at a stage where you can meaningfully change it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the Lelouche and.. uhh his best friend comparison where one tries to rise through the ranks and change the system from the inside vs the other who wants to tear it down and raise it back up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there still some merit to the argument though? you need to establish your character to connect with others. I want to see someone who walks the walk and establishes that ethos with me. People rip on Bernie Sanders all the time for having million dollar homes. In this specific situation it’s a misunderstanding (more likely intentional mischaracterization) on what kind of scale things are applied and where lines are drawn. But the point stands that the disconnect really resonates with a lot of people. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Habit Chain]]></title><description><![CDATA[habits that follow other habits. allows you to minimize your decisions and focus on things that actually matter.  Philosophies supporting my…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/habit-chain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/habit-chain/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/3b6a7ad2371abddebe7e18357a341d79/ef3e1/habit-loop.png&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 89.87341772151898%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAASCAYAAABb0P4QAAAACXBIWXMAAAsTAAALEwEAmpwYAAAB40lEQVQ4y42U+c6iUAzFef+n8RX8bz4TY8AlipGIUXEDcV+xk1+TMogyM02uXC69p6enrU6WZXK9XuX1esl2u5Xb7Sac8f58PiV7ZlJl+JivLed+v0uapjIcDqVWq8lkMpH5fC6LxSK/eLlc5HA46Dmr0+lIr9fTc6wI6jweD1mv19Lv96XdbksQBNJoNMR1XWm1WjIYDDTgdDpVoOVymQNCpszS4SVJEomiSC+Px+OcSRiGstvtJI5j3cOePeDsjd0bID//siROVNuylfXLGbIoALZarTQd0rRgZEDhYE+66F3U7yNl0wEDqNlsyrJQFNImYDAK5OfXj2pL4DIgT6cI9s0oGoVCu/9pn5whGpEG63w+53uYkKI/8BU0/37+4/fG0Njt0lRbghbiIgswWslzXWl7nmpI8+NHny6iSPdkUZmyscUJO51O4vu+BsIPVn9N2V4QnT1VrNfr2tyAYYARgOrzbRKGemZ3P1K29uBpGh2PR50ELN7E+RlB6ARGsQyoDLmAM5rhzISgk2mJbTYbfR+NRqoZRaKVvjW3pgwQrcF4zWYz8TxPC2LNDhijSVHw6Xa71Y1tRYAN0QEHgAsmBRU1gKI8laNXNc9W/f1+//bPUi7ER8pFp28Xyoy+MTPA36MUbT/UndOnAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;habit loop&quot;
        title=&quot;habit loop&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/3b6a7ad2371abddebe7e18357a341d79/f058b/habit-loop.png&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/3b6a7ad2371abddebe7e18357a341d79/c26ae/habit-loop.png 158w,
/static/3b6a7ad2371abddebe7e18357a341d79/6bdcf/habit-loop.png 315w,
/static/3b6a7ad2371abddebe7e18357a341d79/f058b/habit-loop.png 630w,
/static/3b6a7ad2371abddebe7e18357a341d79/ef3e1/habit-loop.png 759w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;habits that follow other habits. allows you to minimize your decisions and focus on things that actually matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Philosophies supporting my Daily Habit Chain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning I strive to get working on my knowledge work as fast as possible so the actual routine is fairly minimal. Some hygiene for myself and the dogs and coffee then it’s a short walk to the office. Then it’s a few exercises to clear my mind like [[inbox-zero]] and morning papers. After that I eat the frog and focus on design work if possible. I try to figure out what decisions I need to make throughout the day and make those decisions, this generally  means that design work (the hardest work) is done in the morning. the break time should be used to address whatever was my biggest distraction from getting into [[flow-state]]. sometimes this is my lower back pain so I’ll do a few stretches. other times it’s my need to socialize so I’ll play with the dog or chat with my coworkers. . sometimes it’s just a general lack of focus. of which can usually be cleared with some meditation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;08:00AM - morning routine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed and Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fetch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hygiene [[skincare-is-selfcare]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee and Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clear photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clear synthesizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Management (Raw Notes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Knowledge (Exocortex)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Notes (Wikis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Creation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mind dump&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;morning papers -&gt; stream of consciousness writing for a while. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thoughts from last nights media intake. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick a topic to write about or revise in inbox. it’s a cornocopia of ideas. if it’s empty that means I’m in some kind of rut and should be mixing up my life or input streams somehow. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create new notes for your [[digital-constellation]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;09:00AM - design work - 4 hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[[deep-work-habit-chain]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;01:00PM - lunch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eat and chat [[the-importance-of-family-meals]]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wash dishes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mouth wash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;02:00PM - mechanical work - 3 hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check Email and Phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stretch
cat camel
child’s pose
cobra
downward facing dog
bent over
leg lock each side
twist each side&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play with Dogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hydration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Variant (Oyatsu no Jikan)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go grab a coffee and snack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;05:00PM - wind down&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dinner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Lunch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fitness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take creatine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put on workout clothes and set out mats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workout according to energy level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place BIG ASS X on whiteboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hygiene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;07:00PM - relax, review, research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feedly articles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;targeted research and inspo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;11:00PM - night routine&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set Workout Clothes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hygiene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relax: Diffuser and Melatonin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Creation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;post &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Beginnings]]></title><description><![CDATA[Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/new-beginnings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/new-beginnings/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove
right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean. A small river named
Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On deer horse aboard tritely yikes and much&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad
Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text
didn’t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and
made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This however showed weasel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well uncritical so misled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this is very interesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goodness much until that fluid owl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the &lt;strong&gt;Italic Mountains&lt;/strong&gt;, she had a last
view back on the skyline of her hometown &lt;em&gt;Bookmarksgrove&lt;/em&gt;, the headline of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;Alphabet Village&lt;/a&gt; and the subline of her own road, the Line
Lane. Pityful a rhetoric question ran over her cheek, then she continued her
way. On her way she met a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overlaid the jeepers uselessly much excluding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nothing the copy said could convince her and so it didn’t take long until a
few insidious Copy Writers ambushed her, made her drunk with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;Longe and Parole&lt;/a&gt; and dragged her into their agency, where
they abused her for their projects again and again. And if she hasn’t been
rewritten, then they are still using her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove
right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your
mouth. Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is
an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the
name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;According a funnily until pre-set or arrogant well cheerful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad
Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text
didn’t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and
made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So baboon this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mounted militant weasel gregariously admonishingly straightly hey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dear foresaw hungry and much some overhung&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rash opossum less because less some amid besides yikes jeepers frenetic
impassive fruitlessly shut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view
back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet
Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rhetoric
question ran over her cheek, then she continued her way. On her way she met a
copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The copy warned the Little Blind Text, that where it came from it would have
been rewritten a thousand times and everything that was left from its origin
would be the word “and” and the Little Blind Text should turn around and
return to its own, safe country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nothing the copy said could convince her and so it didn’t take long until a
few insidious Copy Writers ambushed her, made her drunk with Longe and Parole
and dragged her into their agency, where they abused her for their projects
again and again. And if she hasn’t been rewritten, then they are still using
her. Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Silent delightfully including because before one up barring chameleon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a
large language ocean. A small river named Duden flows by their place and
supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in
which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an
almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the
name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar. The Big Oxmox
advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild
Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn’t listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Wherever far wow thus a squirrel raccoon jeez jaguar this from along&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on
the way. When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a
last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of
Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a
rhetoric question ran over her cheek, then she continued her way. On her way she
met a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Slapped cozy a that lightheartedly and far&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The copy warned the Little Blind Text, that where it came from it would have
been rewritten a thousand times and everything that was left from its origin
would be the word “and” and the Little Blind Text should turn around and return
to its own, safe country. But nothing the copy said could convince her and so it
didn’t take long until a few insidious Copy Writers ambushed her, made her drunk
with Longe and Parole and dragged her into their agency, where they abused her
for their projects again and again.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Second Post!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Wow! I love blogging so much already. Did you know that “despite its name, salted duck eggs can also be made from
chicken eggs, though the…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/my-second-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/my-second-post/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Wow! I love blogging so much already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that “despite its name, salted duck eggs can also be made from
chicken eggs, though the taste and texture will be somewhat different, and the
egg yolk will be less rich.”?
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salted_duck_egg&quot;&gt;Wikipedia Link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I didn’t either.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting! I’m sure I’ll write a lot more interesting things in the future. Oh, and here’s a…]]></description><link>https://tunaphish.me/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tunaphish.me/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure I’ll write a lot more interesting things in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and here’s a great quote from this Wikipedia on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salted_duck_egg&quot;&gt;salted duck eggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A salted duck egg is a Chinese preserved food product made by soaking duck
eggs in brine, or packing each egg in damp, salted charcoal. In Asian
supermarkets, these eggs are sometimes sold covered in a thick layer of salted
charcoal paste. The eggs may also be sold with the salted paste removed,
wrapped in plastic, and vacuum packed. From the salt curing process, the
salted duck eggs have a briny aroma, a gelatin-like egg white and a
firm-textured, round yolk that is bright orange-red in color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/e1596/salty_egg.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75.31645569620254%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMB/8QAFwEAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEEBf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABgik0dWC//8QAGRABAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQACERJC/9oACAEBAAEFAkqW7B5Zovtvk//EABcRAQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREkH/2gAIAQMBAT8B1WX/xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAESL/2gAIAQIBAT8BjT//xAAbEAABBAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIRISIxMv/aAAgBAQAGPwK9GNocyS8hCj//xAAaEAADAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhQYGx/9oACAEBAAE/IXOrA43oOyg9wgU86OZMfwZKypT/2gAMAwEAAgADAAAAEMjv/8QAFxEBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQARIf/aAAgBAwEBPxARwyusv//EABcRAQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAIVH/2gAIAQIBAT8QOoVoX//EAB0QAQEAAgIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAERADFhgSFB0eH/2gAIAQEAAT8QSpwaGjrBSrtHyF9iY8RpUnGRBGqtOcsiDE6fM3AgiXf5M//Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Chinese Salty Egg&quot;
        title=&quot;Chinese Salty Egg&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/828fb/salty_egg.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/ff44c/salty_egg.jpg 158w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/a6688/salty_egg.jpg 315w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/828fb/salty_egg.jpg 630w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/0ede0/salty_egg.jpg 945w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/3ac88/salty_egg.jpg 1260w,
/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/e1596/salty_egg.jpg 2048w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also write code blocks here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; saltyDuckEgg &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;chinese preserved food product&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher’s Stone&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;2001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;2002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;2004&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.github.com/adamschwartz/github-markdown-kitchen-sink/master/README.md&quot;&gt;View raw (TEST.md)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;This is a paragraph.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Header 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Header 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Header 1
========

Header 2
--------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Header 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Header 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Header 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Header 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Header 5&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Header 6&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;# Header 1
## Header 2
### Header 3
#### Header 4
##### Header 5
###### Header 6&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Header 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Header 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Header 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Header 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Header 5&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Header 6&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;# Header 1 #
## Header 2 ##
### Header 3 ###
#### Header 4 ####
##### Header 5 #####
###### Header 6 ######&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus. Vestibulum enim wisi, viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus. Vestibulum enim wisi, viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is a header.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the first list item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the second list item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s some example code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Markdown.generate();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; ## This is a header.
&amp;gt; 1. This is the first list item.
&amp;gt; 2. This is the second list item.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt; Here&amp;#39;s some example code:
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;     Markdown.generate();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Red
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Green
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Blue

&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Red
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Green
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Blue

&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Red
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Green
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Blue&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;code goes&lt;/code&gt; here in this line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; goes here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;- &lt;span class=&quot;token code keyword&quot;&gt;`code goes`&lt;/span&gt; here in this line
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token bold&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token content&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; goes here&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy flour and salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix together with water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Buy flour and salt
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Mix together with water
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Bake&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;code goes&lt;/code&gt; here in this line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; goes here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;1. &lt;span class=&quot;token code keyword&quot;&gt;`code goes`&lt;/span&gt; here in this line
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token bold&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token content&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; goes here&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Paragraph:

    Code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;* * *

***

*****

- - -

---------------------------------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com&quot; title=&quot;Example&quot;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt; link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com&quot;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; has no title attr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title&quot;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt; reference-style link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;This is [an example](http://example.com &amp;quot;Example&amp;quot;) link.

[This link](http://example.com) has no title attr.

This is [an example] [id] reference-style link.

[id]: http://example.com &amp;quot;Optional Title&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;single asterisks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;single underscores&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;double asterisks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;double underscores&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;*single asterisks*

_single underscores_

**double asterisks**

__double underscores__&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paragraph has some &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;code&lt;/code&gt; in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;This paragraph has some `code` in it.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://placehold.it/200x50&quot; alt=&quot;Alt Text&quot; title=&quot;Image Title&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;![Alt Text](https://placehold.it/200x50 &amp;quot;Image Title&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>